<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
    <name>Homebrew Gifts</name>
    <update version="0.0.7">
      <file name="homebrew-gifts.xml" url="https://github.com/StarsSC/Spencer-s-Homebrew-Stuff.git" />
    </update>
  </info>
<element name="Deny The Reaper" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_BOON_DENY_THE_REAPER">
  <description>
    <p>When the final thread of life is about to sever, your mastery over ki allows you to momentarily transcend mortality. Upon failing your third death saving throw, you can choose to open the <strong>Seven Gates of Enlightenment</strong>, channeling pure ki energy through your being for 1 minute.</p>
    <p class="indent">
      <strong>
        <em>Awakening.</em>
      </strong>
      You regain hit points equal to half your hit point maximum (rounded down). In addition, you unlock the full potential of your body, casting aside all restrictions and unleashing the following <em>Gates</em> within:
    </p>
    <p class="indent">
      <strong>
        <em>Gates of Grounding.</em>
      </strong>
      You have advantage on Strength saving throws, and you cannot be knocked prone or moved against your will. In addition, when you use your <em>Flurry of Blows</em> feature, you can expend up to 2 additional Ki points to make one extra unarmed strike per Ki point spent.
    </p>
        <p class="indent">
      <strong>
        <em>Gate of Flow.</em>
      </strong>
          You have advantage on Dexterity saving throws and your movement speed increases by 20 feet. Additionally, if you want to make an attack or unarmed strike against a creature that is beyond your reach, you can expend 1 Ki point to teleport up to 20 feet to a location within range of the target, allowing you to complete the attack or unarmed strike.
    </p>
        <p class="indent">
      <strong>
        <em>Gate of Unity.</em>
      </strong>
          You have advantage on Constitution saving throws. Additionally, when a creature within 20 feet of you that you can see takes damage, you can use your reaction to redirect that damage to yourself instead.
    </p>
        <p class="indent">
      <strong>
        <em>Gate of Vitality.</em>
      </strong>
          At the start of each of your turns, you regain Ki points equal to one roll of your Martial Arts die plus your Wisdom modifier. In addition, once per turn (no action required), you can expend up to 7 Ki points. For each Ki point expended in this way, you regain hit points equal to one roll of your MArtial Arts die plus your Constitution modifier.
    </p>
        <p class="indent">
      <strong>
        <em>Gate of Eloquence.</em>
      </strong>
          You have advantage on Charisma saving throws. In addition, as a bonus action on your turn, you can spend up to 2 ki points to cast the <em>command</em> spell at a level equal to the number of ki points spent.
    </p>
        <p class="indent">
      <strong>
        <em>Gate of Illumination.</em>
      </strong>
          You have advantage on Intelligence saving throws. Additionally, at the start of each of your turns (no action required), you can spend 2 Ki points to gain an additional use of your bonus action and reaction until the start of your next turn.
    </p>
        <p class="indent">
      <strong>
        <em>Gate of Serenity.</em>
      </strong>
          You gain advantage on Wisdom saving throws. In addition, you gain truesight out of 120 feet and creatures cannot gain advantage on attacks against you as you can see through their movements.
    </p>
    <p class="indent">This Epic Boon can be used only once. When the effect of this boon ends, you drop to 1 hit point and fall unconscious until you finish a long rest. You gain 5 levels of Exhaustion immediately, and at the start of your next turn, you gain one more. Using this boon deteriorates your body and disrupts your ki; your maximum number of ki points is halved. This reduction can only be reversed by the <em>wish</em> spell or <em>divine intervention</em>.
    </p>
  </description>
	<setters>
		<set name="category">Homebrew Gifts</set>
		<set name="type">Blessing</set>
		<set name="slot">gift</set>
</element>
</elements>
