<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
    <name>Wondrous Items</name>
    <update version="0.0.71">
      <file name="homebrew-wonders.xml" url="https://github.com/StarsSC/Spencer-s-Homebrew-Stuff.git"/>
    </update>
  </info>
  <element name="The Faustian Burn" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_FAUSTIAN_BURN">
    <description>
	   <p>This replacement limb is forged of blackened steel fused with ember-veined flesh. Faint smoke curls from the knuckles, and the scent of scorched ash lingers wherever you go. It is said to be the result of a desperate bargain with an infernal patron, its power fueled by your soul's slow erosion.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong>Infernal Strike.</strong> The Faustian Burn functions as a magical melee weapon for your unarmed strikes made with that arm dealing an additional 1d4 fire damage.</p>
        <p class="indent"><strong>Ember Grasp (1/Short Rest).</strong> As a bonus action, you can cause the arm to flare with heat for 1 minute. While active:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Your unarmed strikes with the arm deal an extra 1d6 fire damage.</li>
          <li>If you successfully grapple a creature with the arm, it takes 1d6 fire damage at the start of each of its turns while grappled.</li>
        </ul>
        <p class="indent"><strong>Pact Scars.</strong> When you roll a natural 20 on an attack using the arm, you can choose to deal an additional 2d6 fire damage. If you do so, you take fire damage equal to half the total fire damage dealt.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="5">5 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Replacement Arm</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Inter-Dimensional Chalk" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_DIMENSIONAL_COMPASS">
    <description>
	   <p>With this chalk, you can use it to travel long distances on the Material plane and to other planes of existence.</p>
      <p class="indent">You draw a symbol on a door, that you associate with an individual or the plane of existence and knock three times on the door, someone on the other side must open the door or else the spell won't take effect.</p>
      <p class="indent">Anti magic warding spells and charms prevent the enchantment on the door from taking place, making the chalk fizzle and dissipate from the surface.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Chalk</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Dimensional Compass" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_DIMENSIONAL_COMPASS">
    <description>
	   <p><strong>Planar Wayfinder.</strong> Before using this compass, you must choose a plane of existence and spend one minute to align the compass to that plane of existence. When the compass is aligned, it points to the nearest portal or rift that leads to that plane of existence.</p>
      <p class="indent">You can align the compass to the material plane and all elemental planes. You can also align the compass to any plane of existence you have been to before.</p>
      <p class="indent">You may attempt to align the compass to a plane of existence you have never been to by making an Arcana check. Your DM decides the DC for this check, The difficulty depends on your familiarity with the plane of existence and the nature or location of the plane itself. If the check is unsuccessful, the compass may not function at all, or it may become aligned to a different plane.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Compass</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Amulet of the Sea of Stars" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_SEA_OF_STARS">
    <description>
	   <p><strong>Star-Eyed.</strong> Whilst attuned to this amulet you have Darkvision out to a range of 120ft. Additionally you can use a bonus action to channel the energy from this amulet to gain Truesight for 1 hour out to a range of 120ft. You can use this feature once per day.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong>Ancient Amethyst.</strong> Whilst attuned to this amulet you have resistance against Force, Radiant and Necrotic damage.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong>Overseer's Might.</strong> When you are attuned to <em>Astralis - The Eye of the Universe</em> and this amulet, the maximum amount of Dimension Walker charges of the staff is increased by 2.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Amulet</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
      <rules>
        <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION"/>
        <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FORCE"/>
        <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_RADIANT"/>
        <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC"/>
      </rules>
  </element>
    <element name="Amulet of the Indispensable" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_INDISPENSABLE_AMULET">
    <description>
	   <p><strong>Essential Individual.</strong> Whilst you are attuned to this amulet your Constitution score increases by 2, to a maximum of 20.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong>Lifesaver's Dash.</strong> Your speed increases by 20 ft. when moving towards a friendly creature which has dropped to 0 hit points.</p>
      <p class="indent"><strong>Swift Response.</strong> Whenever you heal a creature which has taken damage since the end of your last turn, you may reroll all 1's and 2's on the dice. You may use this feature for Healing spells, abilities and potions.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Amulet</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
      <rules>
        <stat name="constitution" value="2"/>
      </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Bond of the Wildguard" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_BOND_OF_THE_WILDGUARD">
    <description>
	   <p><strong><em>May only be attuned by a Ranger...</em></strong></p>
      <p class="indent"><strong>The Bond of the Wildguard is a set of intertwined bracers and reins that seem to pulse with the heartbeat of nature itself. The bracers are crafted from living vines and reinforced with plates of smooth, polished stone, while the reins are made from braided strands of silver that shimmer in moonlight. When touched, the materials feel as though they are alive, responding subtly to the emotions and intent of the wearer.</strong></p>
      <p class="indent"><strong>Ancient lore states that this artifact was woven by the elemental spirits of the Wilds, at the behest of the first Beastmaster and Cavalier to unify their bond with their animal companions. Legends speak of its creation during an age when nature was under siege by those who sought to exploit its bounties without reverence. The Wildguard was given to champions who vowed to defend the balance of nature and protect its creatures.</strong></p>
      <p class="indent"><strong>When worn, the Bond strengthens the connection between the bearer and their beast companion, granting them an unparalleled synergy. The bond itself hums with a low, soothing resonance, as though it amplifies the unspoken communication between kindred spirits. Those attuned to it report feeling the raw essence of nature coursing through their veins, empowering them to fight not as individuals, but as a unified force with their beast allies.</strong></p>
      <p class="indent"><strong>The Bond of the Wildguard is also said to house the blessing of the Primal Guardians, ancient entities tied to the preservation of life’s natural order. In moments of great peril, these guardians are rumored to manifest briefly to protect their chosen champions, their presence marked by the rustling of unseen leaves and the roar of distant storms.</strong></p>
      <p class="indent"><em>Beastmaster's Bond:</em> Your beast companion gains the following bonuses:
        <ul>
          <li>+4 AC, +30 temporary hit points, and advantage on attack rolls.</li>
          <li>Your companion can make an additional attack when you take the Attack action</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p class="indent"><em>Cavalier's Command:</em> While mounted, you gain the following benefits:
        <ul>
          <li>Enemies within 10 feet of you have disadvantage on attack rolls against anyone other than you.</li>
          <li>Your mount gains advantage on saving throws against spells and effects that would frighten or restrain it.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p class="indent"><em>Primal Rally:</em> As a bonus action, you and your companion can move up to half your speed without provoking opportunity attacks.</p>
      <p class="indent"><em>Alpha's Cry:</em> Once per long rest, you and your companion unleash a primal roar. All allies within 30 feet gain temporary hit points equal to your level and can immediately make one weapon attack as a reaction. Enemies within the same radius must succeed on a DC 18 Wisdom saving throw or become frightened for 1 minute</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
            <p class="indent"><em>Beastmaster's Bond:</em> Your beast companion gains the following bonuses:
        <ul>
          <li>+4 AC, +30 temporary hit points, and advantage on attack rolls.</li>
          <li>Your companion can make an additional attack when you take the Attack action</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p class="indent"><em>Cavalier's Command:</em> While mounted, you gain the following benefits:
        <ul>
          <li>Enemies within 10 feet of you have disadvantage on attack rolls against anyone other than you.</li>
          <li>Your mount gains advantage on saving throws against spells and effects that would frighten or restrain it.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p class="indent"><em>Primal Rally:</em> As a bonus action, you and your companion can move up to half your speed without provoking opportunity attacks.</p>
      <p class="indent"><em>Alpha's Cry:</em> Once per long rest, you and your companion unleash a primal roar. All allies within 30 feet gain temporary hit points equal to your level and can immediately make one weapon attack as a reaction. Enemies within the same radius must succeed on a DC 18 Wisdom saving throw or become frightened for 1 minute</p>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">athletics</set>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">hands</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Trinity of Balance</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="Chaosheart Amulet" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_CHAOSHEART_AMULET">
    <description>
      <p><strong><em>Must be attuned by a Warlock...</em></strong></p>
   	    <p class="indent"><strong>The Chaosheart Amulet is a mesmerizing, otherworldly artifact, its core resembling a living, unblinking eye set within a jagged crystal. The "eye" shifts colors constantly, cycling through hues of fiery orange, icy blue, venomous green, and more, as though it reflects the chaos of the multiverse itself. When attuned, the amulet pulses with faint warmth, synchronizing with its bearer’s heartbeat. The chaotic energy radiating from the artifact hums with whispers, sometimes encouraging, sometimes maddening, but always compelling.</strong></p>
        <p class="indent"><strong>Legend speaks of the Chaosheart being crafted from the shattered essence of an ancient, primordial entity that existed before the alignment of the planes. It is said that the fragment was imbued with sentience by a powerful Chaos Patron who wished to give their warlocks a piece of themselves. Its eye-like design is no mere aesthetic; it is believed to be a window into the chaotic planes, eternally gazing upon the swirling forces of entropy.</strong></p>
        <p class="indent"><strong>While wearing the amulet, its bearer feels a deep connection to the unpredictable and unknowable. However, this connection comes with a price: moments of clarity are often interspersed with intrusive visions of cataclysmic destruction or wild euphoria. To many Chaos warlocks, the Chaosheart is a mark of favor, but to others, it is a burden of untamed power waiting to be unleashed.</strong></p>
      <p class="indent"><em>Chaotic Bolts:</em> Eldritch Blast now deals an additional 1d10 damage of a randomly determined type (roll 1d6: 1 = fire, 2 = cold, 3 = lightning, 4 = acid, 5 = necrotic, 6 = radiant).</p>
      <p class="indent"><em>Ripple of Chaos:</em> When you cast a spell using a spell slot, you can unleash a wave of chaotic energy. Each creature of your choice within 10 feet of you must make a DC 18 Dexterity saving throw or take 2d8 damage of a randomly determined type (roll 1d6 for the damage type). This ability can be used a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier, and all uses refresh after a long rest.</p>
      <p class="indent"><em>Wild Convergence:</em> When you use your Mystic Arcanum, roll 1d4. On a 4, you immediately regain that use after the spell is cast.</p>
      <p class="indent"><em>Chaos Nexus:</em> Once per long rest, you can cchannel the raw energy of chaos into an overwhelming surge of power. For the next 3 rounds:
        <ul>
          <li>When you roll damage for a spell, add an additional 3d6 damage of a randomly determined type (roll 1d6 for each spell).</li>
          <li>Whenever a creature within 30 feet of you succeeds on a saving throw against one of your spells, roll a d20. On a 15 or higher, the creature takes half the damage the spell would have dealt, regardless of the saving throw result</li>
          <li>Spells you cast during this time cannot be countered or dispelled.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
            <p class="indent"><em>Chaotic Bolts:</em> Eldritch Blast now deals an additional 1d10 damage of a randomly determined type (roll 1d6: 1 = fire, 2 = cold, 3 = lightning, 4 = acid, 5 = necrotic, 6 = radiant).</p>
      <p class="indent"><em>Ripple of Chaos:</em> When you cast a spell using a spell slot, you can unleash a wave of chaotic energy. Each creature of your choice within 10 feet of you must make a DC 18 Dexterity saving throw or take 2d8 damage of a randomly determined type (roll 1d6 for the damage type). This ability can be used a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier, and all uses refresh after a long rest.</p>
      <p class="indent"><em>Wild Convergence:</em> When you use your Mystic Arcanum, roll 1d4. On a 4, you immediately regain that use after the spell is cast.</p>
      <p class="indent"><em>Chaos Nexus:</em> Once per long rest, you can cchannel the raw energy of chaos into an overwhelming surge of power. For the next 3 rounds:
        <ul>
          <li>When you roll damage for a spell, add an additional 3d6 damage of a randomly determined type (roll 1d6 for each spell).</li>
          <li>Whenever a creature within 30 feet of you succeeds on a saving throw against one of your spells, roll a d20. On a 15 or higher, the creature takes half the damage the spell would have dealt, regardless of the saving throw result</li>
          <li>Spells you cast during this time cannot be countered or dispelled.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">neck</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Trinity of Balance</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="Robes of the Ancients" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_ANCIENT_ROBES">
    <description>
     <p>These finely crafted robes are designed for those who engage in martial combat, combining style with functionality. When worn, the Robes of the Ancients grant the following benefits:
      <ul>
	      <li>+1 to Armor Class.</li>
	      <li>If the wearer has an Unarmored Defense feature (such as a Monk's Unarmored Defense), they gain a +1 bonus to AC in addition to the benefits of their Unarmored Defense.</li>
	      <li><strong>Ki Surge:</strong> Once per short rest, the wearer can spend 1 Ki point to gain advantage on their next attack roll or saving throw.</li>
	      <li><strong>Martial Precision:</strong> Once per day, as a bonus action, they can gain advantage on all attack rolls for the next minute.</li>
      </ul>
     </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">robes</set>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">2500</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="slot">back</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
      <stat name="ac:misc" value="2"/>
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Bright Idea Rare" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_BRIGHT_IDEA_RARE">
    <description>
	   <p>An ornately bound book with pages twinkling like the night sky. This item begins as Rare and through time, accomplishment, and growth, can increase in rarity to Very Rare, then Legendary (according to your GM). You must have an Intelligence score of 16 or greater to attune to this item. This item can be used as an arcane focus and spellbook.
	   </p>
		   <p class="indent">
         <strong>
           <em>Rare</em>
         </strong>
         This item has a number of charges equal to your Intelligence modifier. When you attune to this item, you can learn one additional cantrip of your choice that you can cast while attuned to this item.</p>
       <p class="indent">
         <strong>
           <em>Rewrite</em>
         </strong>
         Your knowledge of arcane formulas allows you to alter the nature of your magical arsenal. As you cast a spell, you can spend a charge to alter it in one of the following ways. A spell can't be altered in more than one way:
         <ul>
           <li><strong>Amplify:</strong> If the spell deals damage, reroll any roll of 1 or 2 on the damage dice, but you must use the new roll</li>
           <li><strong>Condense:</strong> If the spell deals damage in an area of effect such as a sphere, line, or cone, you can halve the area of effect (ex. 20 feet to 10 feet). Each creature in the spell's area of effect makes their saving throw with disadvantage.</li>
           <li><strong>Type:</strong> If the spell deals one of the following damage types, you can replace it with another one of the following types: Acid, Cold, Fire, Lightning, Poison. If the spell has multiple damage types, you can change only one of them.</li>
           <li><strong>Lengthen:</strong> If the spell has a range of at least 5 feet and doesn't have a range of Self, you can increase the range of the spell by 30 times your Intelligence modifier.</li>
           <li><strong>Timing:</strong> You can change the casting time of a spell from 1 action to 1 bonus action, or vice-versa.</li>
	 </ul>
       </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
    <element name="Bright Idea Very Rare" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_BRIGHT_IDEA_VERYRARE">
    <description>
	   <p>An ornately bound book with pages twinkling like the night sky. This item begins as Rare and through time, accomplishment, and growth, can increase in rarity to Very Rare, then Legendary (according to your GM). You must have an Intelligence score of 16 or greater to attune to this item. This item can be used as an arcane focus and spellbook.
	   </p>
		   <p class="indent">
         <strong>
           <em>Rare</em>
         </strong>
         This item has a number of charges equal to your Intelligence modifier. When you attune to this item, you can learn one additional cantrip of your choice that you can cast while attuned to this item.</p>
       <p class="indent">
         <strong>
           <em>Rewrite</em>
         </strong>
         Your knowledge of arcane formulas allows you to alter the nature of your magical arsenal. As you cast a spell, you can spend a charge to alter it in one of the following ways. A spell can't be altered in more than one way:
         <ul>
           <li><strong>Amplify:</strong> If the spell deals damage, reroll any roll of 1 or 2 on the damage dice, but you must use the new roll</li>
           <li><strong>Condense:</strong> If the spell deals damage in an area of effect such as a sphere, line, or cone, you can halve the area of effect (ex. 20 feet to 10 feet). Each creature in the spell's area of effect makes their saving throw with disadvantage.</li>
           <li><strong>Type:</strong> If the spell deals one of the following damage types, you can replace it with another one of the following types: Acid, Cold, Fire, Lightning, Poison. If the spell has multiple damage types, you can change only one of them.</li>
           <li><strong>Lengthen:</strong> If the spell has a range of at least 5 feet and doesn't have a range of Self, you can increase the range of the spell by 30 times your Intelligence modifier.</li>
           <li><strong>Timing:</strong> You can change the casting time of a spell from 1 action to 1 bonus action, or vice-versa.</li>
	 </ul>
       </p>
           <p class="indent">
             <strong>
               <em>Very Rare</em>
             </strong>
             You can learn one additional cantrip to cast while attuned to this item.</p>
           <p class="indent">
             <strong>
               <em>Breach</em>
             </strong>
             Your magic shreds through magical defenses with ease. Spells you cast ignore bonuses to AC and immunities or resistances granted by magical means (ex. Shield of Faith, Ring of Resistance, Protection of Energy, etc).</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Bright Idea Legendary" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_BRIGHT_IDEA_LEGENDARY">
    <description>
	   <p>An ornately bound book with pages twinkling like the night sky. This item begins as Rare and through time, accomplishment, and growth, can increase in rarity to Very Rare, then Legendary (according to your GM). You must have an Intelligence score of 16 or greater to attune to this item. This item can be used as an arcane focus and spellbook.
	   </p>
		   <p class="indent">
         <strong>
           <em>Rare</em>
         </strong>
         This item has a number of charges equal to your Intelligence modifier. When you attune to this item, you can learn one additional cantrip of your choice that you can cast while attuned to this item.</p>
       <p class="indent">
         <strong>
           <em>Rewrite</em>
         </strong>
         Your knowledge of arcane formulas allows you to alter the nature of your magical arsenal. As you cast a spell, you can spend a charge to alter it in one of the following ways. A spell can't be altered in more than one way:
         <ul>
           <li><strong>Amplify:</strong> If the spell deals damage, reroll any roll of 1 or 2 on the damage dice, but you must use the new roll</li>
           <li><strong>Condense:</strong> If the spell deals damage in an area of effect such as a sphere, line, or cone, you can halve the area of effect (ex. 20 feet to 10 feet). Each creature in the spell's area of effect makes their saving throw with disadvantage.</li>
           <li><strong>Type:</strong> If the spell deals one of the following damage types, you can replace it with another one of the following types: Acid, Cold, Fire, Lightning, Poison. If the spell has multiple damage types, you can change only one of them.</li>
           <li><strong>Lengthen:</strong> If the spell has a range of at least 5 feet and doesn't have a range of Self, you can increase the range of the spell by 30 times your Intelligence modifier.</li>
           <li><strong>Timing:</strong> You can change the casting time of a spell from 1 action to 1 bonus action, or vice-versa.</li>
	 </ul>
       </p>
           <p class="indent">
             <strong>
               <em>Very Rare</em>
             </strong>
             You can learn one additional cantrip to cast while attuned to this item.</p>
           <p class="indent">
             <strong>
               <em>Breach</em>
             </strong>
             Your magic shreds through magical defenses with ease. Spells you cast ignore bonuses to AC and immunities or resistances granted by magical means (ex. Shield of Faith, Ring of Resistance, Protection of Energy, etc).</p>
           <p class="indent">
             <strong>
               <em>Legendary</em>
             </strong>
             When you use the Rewrite property you can choose to alter the affected spell in one additional way without spending an additional charge. When a creature within 120 feet of you casts a spell, you are aware of it and know the direction of the caster as you can sense all the magic around you.</p>
           <p class="indent">
             <strong>
               <em>Overrule</em>
             </strong>
             Your mastery of the arcane arts has advanced to such a degree that all magic is at your beck and call. You can use your reaction to use the Rewrite property to alter spells cast by other creatures within 120 feet of you. An unwilling creature must succeed on an Intelligence (Arcana) check contested by your Intelligence (Arcana) check.</p>
             <p class="indent">The rewrite property gains the following ways to alter a spell:</p>
             <p class="indent">
               <strong>
                 <em>Diminish:</em>
               </strong>
               If the spell deals damage, reroll any damage dice that rolled for maximum damage.</p>
             <p class="indent">
               <strong>
                 <em>Redirect:</em>
               </strong>
               If the spell targets one creature, you can redirect the spell to target another creature within range of the original caster.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	 <element name="Wings of the Windborne" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_WINGS_OF_THE_WINDBORNE">
    <description>
	   <p>This finely crafted leather backpack, adorned with silver clasps and intricate feather-like stitching, contains an ancient magical enchantment. When worn, the backpack appears to be a normal traveler's bag, but upon the command word, it transforms into a pair of magnificent wings made of shimmering, ethereal feathers.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Transformation</em>
        </strong>
        As a bonus action, the wearer can speak the command word, causing the backpack to unfold and transform into a pair of wings. While the wings are active, the wearer gains a flying speed of 60 feet.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Wing Effects</em>
        </strong>
        The wings can remain active for up to 1 hour per day. The time can be split into multiple uses, but the total cannot exceed 1 hour. They regain their full flying speed at dawn, and if they are deployed while falling, the wearer immediately benefits from the feather fall spell.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Weightless Flight</em>
        </strong>
        While flying, the wearer experiences almost no burden from carrying the backpack, as it magically lightens their load.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="slot">back</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Mimicry Coin" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_MIMICRY_COIN">
    <description>
	   <p>This small coin, about the size of a silver piece, bears intricate engravings of a raven. When held in hand, it radiates a faint aura of mischievous charm.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Mimicry</em>
        </strong>
        The Mimicry Coin grants its wielder the ability to mimic sounds and voices with uncanny accuracy, akin to that of a Kenku. The coin holds a limited reservoir of mimicry power, allowing the wielder to mimic any sound or voice they have heard, replicating it with precision.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        By expending 1 charge from the coin, the wielder can activate the Mimicry ability for 1 minute. The coin has 4 charges in total, and it regains 1d4 expended charges at dawn.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        If the wielder already possesses the ability to mimic, they gain advantage on their mimicry checks for 1 minute instead when a charge is expended.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Coin</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Jar of Eyeballs" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_JAR_OF_EYEBALLS">
    <description>
	   <p>Whenever you kill a hostile creature, you can choose to remove its eyeballs and place them into a jar. About 50 eyeballs can fit into the jar. During a short or long rest, if the jar is covered in fine cloth for at least 20 minutes, each eyeball in the jar transforms into a gold coin. Eyeballs of creatures that weren't hostile at the time they were killed remain untransformed.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Jar</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="Aether Vial" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_AETHER_VILE">
    <description>
	   <p>This small ornate glass vial contains a mysterious blue misty liquid inside. The Aether Vial has 1d4 doses. As a bonus action, you or another creature can consume a dose of the liquid from the vial. After drinking it, the consumer can choose one effect from the following:
       <ul>
         <li><strong>Aetheric Surge:</strong> The consumer gains advantage on the next saving throw they make within the next minute.</li>
         <li><strong>Arcane Vitality:</strong> The consumer gains temporary hit points equal to 1d8 + their proficiency bonus + their choice of Charisma, Intelligence, or Wisdom modifier.</li>
         <li><strong>Ethereal Resistance:</strong> The consumer gains resistance to all damage of spells for 1 minute.</li>
         <li><strong>Mystical Agility:</strong> The consumer's speed increases by 10 feet, and they don't provoke opportunity attacks for 1 minute.</li>
       </ul>
     </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Wonderous Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	 <element name="Azure Flow" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_AZURE_FLOW">
    <description>
	    <p>This ring appears to be crafted from flowing light blue water, with gentle ripples constantly moving around its band. When submerged in a natural source of water (such as a pond, lake, river, or sea) for at least 1 minute, the ring becomes imbued with the essence of that water, adopting its color, scent, and taste.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Aquatic Empowerment</em>
        </strong>
        While attuned to the Azure Flow, the wearer gains the ability to speak and understand Aquan. Additionally, the wearer gains a unique passive benefit based on the specific source of water from which the ring is currently imbued.</p>
      <p>
        <ul>
          <li><strong>Pond.</strong> The wearer gains a sense of serenity and tranquility, gaining a +1 bonus on Wisdom saving throws against being frightened</li>
          <li><strong>Lake.</strong> The wearer feels a connection to the depths, gaining a +1 bonus on Athletics checks related to swimming and diving</li>
          <li><strong>River.</strong> The wearer gains the strength of ever-flowing river streams, gaining a bonus +1 bonus on Strength saving throws to avoid being knocked prone or pushed.</li>
          <li><strong>Sea/Ocean.</strong> The wearer harnesses the boundless energy of the ocean, allowing them to cast the Shape Water cantrip at will.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="type">Ring</set>
      <set name="rarity">Common</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Soulscent Bloom" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_SOULSCENT_BLOOM">
    <description>
	    <p>A jade carved into the shape of a flower. A phantom scent, here one instant and gone the next, swirls around it.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        When attuned to the Soulscent Bloom, the bearer gains the ability to cast the Bless spell once per day without expending a spell slot. Additionally, when the bearer casts Bless using the Soulscent Bloom, each creature affected by the spell gains temporary hit points equal to 1d6 + the bearer's proficiency bonus</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Amulet of Intertwining" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_AMULET_OF_INTERTWINING">
    <description>
	    <p>Gold chain attached to a glass diamond. Inside you can see a blue-red ball of mysterious energy.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Duality</em>
        </strong>
        Whenever you successfully hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend a spell slot. The attack deals an additional 1d8 force damage for each spell slot level expended, up to a maximum of 9d8.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        Furthermore, when you cast a spell using a spell slot of 1st level or higher, you can choose to sacrifice hit points equal to 1d6 for each level you wish to upcast the spell, up to a maxiumum of 9d6 hit points lost. However, you cannot upcast the spell to a level higher than your highest available spell slot (the spell slot can already be expended), limited to a maximum of 9th level. If your hit points would be reduced to 0 because of this effect, the spell is cast before you become unconcious. You cannot sacrifice more hit points than you currently have.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">neck</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
		<element name="Evocation Key" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_EVOCATION_KEY">
    <description>
	    <p>The Evocation Key appears as a twisted and unpolished golden key with colored symbols representing various types of evocation magic at its head. When the key touches a weapon or armor (magical or non-magical) and a spell from the school of evocation, with an associated damage type, is cast on it, the key begins to absorb and redistribute the spell's energy...</p>
	    <p class="indent">
        If the key is touching a weapon, the weapon gains a +1 bonus to both attack and damage rolls, up to a maximum of +4. Additionally, the weapon becomes magical if it wasn't already, and it deals an additional 1d6 damage of the spell's damage type on a successful hit.</p>
	    <p class="indent">
        If they key is touching an armor, the armor gains a +1 bonus to its AC, up to a maximum of +4. Furthermore, the armor becomes magical if it wasn't already, and the wearer gains resistance to the spell's damage type.</p>
      <p>Once the energy transfer is complete, the Evocation Key becomes a non-magical golden key. However, perhads there's a door somewhere that this key could unlock.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="Greaves of Chain Lightning" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_GREAVES_OF_CHAIN_LIGHTNING">
    <description>
	    <p>These finely crafted leather and iron greaves crackle with arcane lightning. As a bonus action, you can activate the greaves, gaining the following benefits for 1 minute:</p>
		    <p class="indent">
			    <strong>
				    <em>Galvanic Charge.</em>
			    </strong>
			    You gain resistance to lightning damage, and your attacks deal an additional 1d6 lightning damage on a hit.</p>
		    <p class="indent">
			    <strong>
				    <em>Bolt.</em>
			    </strong>
			    Your speed increases by 10 feet. Additionally, you can take the Dash action as a bonus action on each of your turns for the duration.</p>
		    <p>Once you activate the greaves, you can't do so again until you finish a long rest. If you score a critical hit or are subjected to a critical hit while the greaves are active, you gain one additional use of this ability. This additional use must be expended before your next long rest.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">athletics</set>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">legs</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="Shifter Arrow" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_SHIFTER_ARROW">
    <description>
	    <p>This arrow has an arrowhead engraved with 3 golden teardrops that seem to shimmer moreso in the sunlight.</p>
	    <p class="indent">
		    <strong>
			    <em>Shift.</em>
		    </strong>
		    Whenever you fire this arrow, you may choose to have this arrow come back to you or if not, summon a spectral arrow to take its place to fire.
	    </p>
	    <p class="indent">
		    <strong>
			    <em>Bloodlust.</em>
		    </strong>
		    Attacks against the same target increase in damage by 2 for each consecutive hit. There is no limit to the damage, just in what you give for it.
	    </p>
		    <p class="indent">
			    <strong>
				    <em>Cursed.</em>
			    </strong>
			    You cannot get rid of this arrow, it is eternally soulbound to the wielder.
		    </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Unique</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="Bracer of the Emerald Stag" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_BRACER_OF_EMERALD_STAG">
    <description>
	    <p>May only be attuned to a Cleric, Paladin, or Ranger.</p>
	    <p class="indent">
		    <strong>
			    <em>Thundering Hooves.</em>
		    </strong>
		    If you make a ranged weapon attack while attuned to this bracer you may use a bonus action to empower the attack with this bracer. On a successful hit the attack deals an extra 3d8 Thunder damage. You can use this feature twice per long rest.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Blessing of the Stag.</em>
        </strong>
        You can use an action to heal and inspire one creature within 30ft. of you using this bracer. Make a Nature check, the creature heals for an amount equal to that number. Additionally, they gain a d8 Inspiration die which they can use on any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check within the next 10 minutes. You can use this feature once per long rest.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">athletics</set>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">hands</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Crown of the Great Wolf" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_CROWN_OF_GREAT_WOLF">
    <description>
<p class="indent">
  <strong>
    <em>Mind of the Wolf.</em>
  </strong>
  While attuned to this crown you have darkvision up to 90ft. You are immune to being Frightened or Charmed and have advantage on saving throws against being Stunned. Additionally you may add your proficiency bonus to Survival checks you make to track other creatures.
</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
        <em>Final Battle.</em>
        </strong>
        If you drop to 0 hit points while attuned to this crown, you regain 5d12 hit points when you roll a successful death save or when you regain any number of hit points. You can benefit from this feature once per long rest
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Parts of a Whole.</em>
        </strong>
        If you are also attuned to the Hide of the Great Wolf, the AC of that armor increases by 1. If you are attuned to the Gloves of the Great Wolf, they deal 1d8 Necrotic damage instead of 1d6.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">head</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION"/>
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Gloves of the Great Wolf" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_GLOVES_OF_GREAT_WOLF">
    <description>
      <p>Requires attunement by a Druid or Monk</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Dark Claws.</em>
        </strong>
        When wearing these gauntlets, your unarmed strikes deal an extra 1d6 Necrotic damage. This bonus is also applied to attacks you make while you are Wild Shaped or Polymorphed.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Bloodthirst.</em>
        </strong>
        Whenever you reduce a creature to 0 hit points, you gain advantage on your next attack roll within the next minute.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Ravager of the Divine.</em>
        </strong>
        Whenever you receive Fire, Lightning, Radiant, or Thunder damage, you may use your reaction to reduce that damage. Make a Wisdom saving throw. The DC equals 10 or a number equal to half of the damage, whichever is higher. On a successful save you reduce the damage by 2d6+ your Wisdom modifier. You may use this feature twice per long rest.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">athletics</set>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">hands</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Satchel of Sustenance" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_SUSTENANCE_SATCHEL">
    <description>
	<p>The Satchel of Sustenance is a remarkable and essential item for any adventurer, crafted from durable, enchanted leather with intricate embroidery depicting scenes of bountiful harvests and feasts. This satchel combines the expansive capacity of a bag of holding with unique magical properties specifically attuned to preserving and providing nourishment. The interior of the Satchel of Sustenance is vast, capable of holding an impressive array of items without ever becoming cumbersome. What sets this satchel apart is its ability to preserve food indefinitely; no matter how long it is stored, food remains fresh and unspoiled, ready to be consumed at any time.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Extradimensional Stockpile</em>
        </strong>
        This bag functions as a Bag of Holding with the extra property that food and drink does not decay when it is stored inside the bag.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Commoner's Feast.</em>
        </strong>
        You can put a gold coin in the bag and speak a command word which consumes the coin. The bag fills with enough food and drink to sustain 5 humanoids for 1 day. The food consists of various breads, nuts, fruits, vegetables and raw meats. The drinks are an assortement of juices and fresh water. The satchel can store up to 10 of these feasts before it is completely filled up. You can use this feature 5 times per day.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="15">15 lb.</set>
      <set name="stash" lb="500" weightless="true">true</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="Immortal Amulet" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_IMMORTAL_AMULET">
    <description>
	<p>The amulet deepens your connection with death. You can use an action to touch a corpse or undead to experieence a short sequence of images on its final moments before death. Once you use this feature you cannot do so again until the next dawn.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">neck</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="Moonsliver Cloak" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_MOONSLIVER_CLOAK">
    <description>
     <p>The Moonsliver Cloak is an enchanting garment woven from the finest silken threads, imbued with the ethereal essence of moonlight itself. This cloak, lightweight and flowing, shimmers with a delicate silvery hue, reminiscent of the moon's glow on a clear night. The fabric is soft to the touch, yet incredibly durable, designed to withstand the rigors of any adventure.</p>
      <p>The cloak grants the wearer these benefits;
        <ul>
          <li>The wearer may become invisible as a bonus action while outdoors in moonlight</li>
          <li>+1 to AC and all saving throws</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">cloak</set>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="slot">shoulders</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
      <stat name="ac:misc" value="1"/>
      <stat name="strength:save:misc" value="1"/>
      <stat name="dexterity:save:misc" value="1"/>
      <stat name="constitution:save:misc" value="1"/>
      <stat name="intelligence:save:misc" value="1"/>
      <stat name="wisdom:save:misc" value="1"/>
      <stat name="charisma:save:misc" value="1"/>
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Hood of the Dragonturtle" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_DRAGONTURTLE_HOOD">
    <description>
      <p>The Hood of the Dragonturtle is a majestic and awe-inspiring piece of headgear, crafted with the scales and essence of the legendary Dragonturtle. This hood is renowned for its distinctive design, which combines the robust, textured scales of the Dragonturtle with elegant craftsmanship. The scales shimmer with hues of deep green, azure, and hints of gold, reflecting the mystical aura of its origin.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Fortitude of the Deep.</em>
        </strong>
        When you are attuned to this hood you gain a +4 to your Constitution ability score.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Dark Ocean Ancestry.</em>
        </strong>
        You gain Darkvision up to 120ft. Additionally you can breathe underwater.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Steam Breath.</em>
        </strong>
        As an action, you exhale steam in a 20ft cone. Each creature in that area has to make a Constitution saving throw (DC 18). Taking 2d8 Fire damage on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful save. The damage increases to 3d8 at 6th level, 4d8 at 11th level, and 5d8 at 16th level. You can not use this feature again until you finish a short or a long rest. Being underwater doesn't grant resistance against this damage.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">head</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION"/>
      <stat name="constitution" value="4"/>
      <stat name="ac:misc" value="1"/>
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Cloak of Solitude" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_CLOAK_OF_SOLITUDE">
    <description>
      <p>The Cloak of Solitude was crafted centuries ago by the enigmatic sorceress Elandra, known for her deep wisdom and solitary nature. Elandra, seeking refuge from a world filled with treachery and deceit, imbued the cloak with powerful enchantments to protect herself from the myriad poisons of her enemies. The forcefield, a unique feature of the cloak, was added to ensure her peace and solitude, gently pushing away any who attempted to intrude upon her sanctuary. Legends say that Elandra wove her longing for solitude into every thread, creating an artifact that not only shields its wearer from harm but also grants them the tranquility she so desperately sought. The cloak has since passed through the hands of many, each owner finding in it a profound sense of protection and peace.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Self-Isolation.</em>
        </strong>
        You have advantage on all Constitution saving throws whenever there is no other creature within 5ft. of you.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Antidote.</em>
        </strong>
        You can cast the spell Protection from Poison using this cloak. You can use this feature once per long rest.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Master of Distancing.</em>
        </strong>
        As an action you create a short burst of an arcane forcefield around you. All creatures within 5ft. of you have to make a Strength saving throw (DC10 + your Constitution modifier). On a failed save they are pushed 5ft. away from you. You can use this feature twice per long rest.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">cloak</set>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">shoulders</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
      <stat name="constitution:save:misc" value="1"/>
    </rules>
  </element>
	<element name="Firedrake's Grasp" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_FIREDRAKE_GRASP">
    <description>
      <p>Crafted by Orcus the Demon Lords subservients out of the scales of a dragon, made to empower their vassal knights, this gauntlet gifts those who wear it with the draconic aspect of rending claws and fiery blood.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Burning Touch.</em>
        </strong>
        The gauntlet burns with a deep heat that does not harm you. While grappling a creature, you can use a bonus action to deal 1d4 fire damage to them.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Claws of Flame.</em>
        </strong>
        While wearing the gauntlet, your unarmed attacks are improved. They deal 1d6 fire or slashing damage plus your Charisma Modifier. If you have the martial arts class feature, you can use your unarmed damage die and still choose to deal fire or flashing damage with your unarmed attacks.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Firedrake's Breath</em>
        </strong>
        You can use an action to produce a torrent of flames from the gauntlet in a 20-foot cone. Each creature inside it must make a DC 14 Dexterity saving throw or suffer 5d6 + your Charisma modifier fire damage. You can do so once per long rest.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">athletics</set>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">hands</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Cosmic Coronet" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_COSMIC_CORONET">
  <description>
    <p>The thrall of cosmic power, of infinite potential; who could resist? A golden crown roiling with interstellar energy. While attuned to this item you can speak, read, and write Celestial can use it as an arcane focus. This item has 4 charges and regains 1d4 charges daily at dawn. Through time, accomplishment, and growth, this item can grow into its Awakened state, then into its Exalted state (according to your DM).
    </p>
    <p class="indent">
      <strong>
        <em>Dormant.</em>
      </strong>
      The crown grants the following benefits in its dormant state;
        <ul><li>While attuned to this item you gain a +1 bonus to spell attack rolls.</li>
	<li><em>Protostar.</em> When you roll for damage as a result of a spell that targets a single creature you can spend up to 3 charges to increase the amount of damage dice you roll by the number of charges spent.</li>
	</ul>
      </p>
	  <p class="indent">
		  <strong>
			  <em>Awakened.</em>
		  </strong>
		  When the crown reaches an awakened state, it gains the following properties;
		  <ul>
			  <li>You gain a +2 bonus to spell attack rolls.</li>
        <li>This item now can hold up to 6 charges and regains 1d6+1 charges daily at dawn.</li>
        <li><em>Black Hole.</em> When you or a creature within 40 feet of you is targeted by a spell of 6th level or lower that targets only a single creature, you can use your reaction to absorb the magic of the spell, canceling its effect. This item then gains a number of charges equal to the level of the absorbed spell. Once you use this property it can't be used again until to finish a long rest.</li>
		  </ul>
	  </p>
    <p class="indent">
      <strong>
        <em>Exalted.</em>
      </strong>
      When the crown reaches an exalted state, it gains the following properties;
      <ul>
        <li>You gain a +3 bonus to spell attack rolls</li>
        <li>This item now can hold up to 8 charges and regains 1d8+2 charges daily at dawn</li>
        <li><em>Constellation.</em> You can spend 7 charges to cast the Crown of Stars spell. Once you use this property, it cannot be used again for 1d6+1 number of days. When you make a spell attack against a creature with a mote created by the Crown of Stars spell while attuned to this item, you can use the Protostar property to increase the number of damage dice you roll for that spell attack.</li>
        <li><em>Shooting Star.</em> You can cast the Wish spell without expending a spell slot. When you cast the spell through this item, your attunement to it is broken and this item vanishes, back to the realm from whence it came.</li>
      </ul>
    </p>
  </description>
	  <setters>
		  <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
		  <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
		  <set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
		  <set name="slot">head</set>
		  <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
		  <set name="attunement">true</set>
		  <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
	  </setters>
  </element>
</elements>
