<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
    <name>Armor</name>
    <update version="0.0.31">
      <file name="homebrew-armor.xml" url="https://github.com/StarsSC/Spencer-s-Homebrew-Stuff.git"/>
    </update>
  </info>
  <element name="Ironroot Plate" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_IRONPLATE_ROOT">
	  <description>
      <p>This armor seems to fuse with the ground as if its part of the roots of a tree, granting advantage on saving throws to resist being moved or knocked prone.</p>
	  </description>
	  <setters>
		  <set name="category">Homebrew Armor</set>
		  <set name="cost" currency="gp">8000</set>
		  <set name="weight" lb="45">45 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">body</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="armor">Medium</set>
      <set name="armorClass">14 + Dex modifier</set>
      <set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SCALE_MAIL</set>
	  </setters>
		      <rules>
        <stat name="ac:armored:armor" value="14"/>
      </rules>
	</element>
  	<element name="Shimmering Mantle" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_SHIMMERING_MANTLE">
	  <description>
		<p><strong>"This Mantle turns darkness into beauty, shielding its wearer with the quiet brilliance of hope."</strong> ~High Enchanter Aelindra Lightrune</p>
      <p class="indent">Grants advantage on saving throws against being blinded, as the fabric glows faintly to counteract magical darkness.</p>
	  </description>
	  <setters>
		  <set name="category">Homebrew Armor</set>
		  <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
		  <set name="weight" lb="13">13 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">body</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="enhancement">2</set>
      <set name="armor">Light</set>
      <set name="armorClass">12 + Dex modifier</set>
      <set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_STUDDED_LEATHER</set>
	  </setters>
	</element>
  <element name="Bastion of Dusk" type="Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_ARMOR_DND_HOMEBREW_BASTION_OF_DUSK">
	<description>
	    <p><strong>"This armor stands as a fortress in the fading light, shielding its wearer with the unbreakable resolve of the approaching night."</strong> ~Venryn Duskforge</p>
			</description>
	<setters>
	    <set name="category">Homebrew Armor</set>
	    <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
	    <set name="weight" lb="65">65 lb.</set>
	    <set name="container">Heavy</set>
	    <set name="armor">Heavy</set>
	    <set name="type">Armor</set>
	    <set name="slot">body</set>  
	  </setters>
	  <rules>
	    <stat name="ac:armored:armor" value="19"/>
	    <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC"/>
	  </rules>
	</element>
  <element name="Shield of Missile Attraction" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_MISSILE_ATTRACTION_SHIELD">
	  <description>
      <p>This shield has a slight magical presence that seems to act like a magnet for fast moving projectiles. As a reaction, you may cause a ranged attack that is directed at an ally within 10 ft to target the wearer instead.</p>
		</description>
	  <setters>
		  <set name="keywords">shield</set>
	    <set name="category">Homebrew Armor</set>
	    <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
	    <set name="weight" lb="6">6 lb.</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
	    <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
	    <set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
	  </setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Unyielding Scale" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_UNYIELDING_SCALE">
	  <description><p>This scale mail armor has been imbued with protective magic, enhancing its durability. The wearer gains +1 to AC, advantage on saving throws against being grappled or restrained, and does not impose disadvantage on Stealth checks.</p>
	  </description>
	  <setters>
		  <set name="category">Homebrew Armor</set>
		  <set name="cost" currency="gp">3000</set>
		  <set name="weight" lb="45">45 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">body</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="enhancement">1</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="armor">Medium</set>
      <set name="armorClass">14 + Dex modifier</set>
      <set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SCALE_MAIL</set>
	  </setters>
		      <rules>
        <stat name="ac:armored:armor" value="14"/>
        <stat name="ac:armored:enhancement" value="1" bonus="enhancement"/>
      </rules>
	</element>
  	<element name="Hide of the Great Wolf" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_HIDE_OF_GREAT_WOLF">
	  <description>
		<p class="indent">
      <strong>
        <em>Vigor.</em>
      </strong>
      While wearing this armor you gain resistance to Cold damage.
    </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
        <em>Pack Tactics.</em>
        </strong>
        While wearing this armor you have advantage on the first attack roll of your turn if at least one of your allies is within 5ft. of your target and the ally isn't incapacitated
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Avatar of the Wolf.</em>
        </strong>
        You can use an action to transform into the Winterwolf for 1 hour. Your AC in this form is 12 + your Dexterity modifier. Additionally you can make a multiattack in this form, making two attacks with your bite. You can revert to your normal form earlier by using a bonus action on your turn. You automatically revert if you fall Unconscious, drop to 0 hit points, or die. Other rules that apply to the druid Wild Shape feature apply to this feature as well. You can use this feature once per long rest.
      </p>
	  </description>
	  <setters>
		  <set name="category">Homebrew Armor</set>
		  <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
		  <set name="weight" lb="13">13 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">body</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="enhancement">1</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="armor">Medium</set>
      <set name="armorClass">14 + Dex modifier</set>
      <set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LEATHER</set>
	  </setters>
      <rules>
        <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_COLD"/>
        <stat name="ac:armored:armor" value="14"/>
        <stat name="ac:armored:enhancement" value="1" bonus="enhancement"/>
      </rules>
	</element>
  <element name="Tombstone Shield" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_TOMBSTONE_SHIELD">
	  <description>
      <p>The Tombstone Shield is a grim and imposing shield, forged with a dark and somber aesthetic that evokes the essence of the grave. Crafted from a heavy, darkened metal, the shield has the appearance of a weathered tombstone, with rough edges and a surface marred by time and battles. Its surface is engraved with intricate, morbid designs, depicting scenes of death and the afterlife, and it radiates an aura of eerie stillness.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Spirit Absorbtion.</em>
        </strong>
        When a humoid creature dies within 15ft of you while carrying this shield, you can use your reaction to absorb its spirit. The name of the creature is carved on the shield, for a maximum of 10 names. When found, the shield has 1d10 names on it already.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Guardian Angel</em>
        </strong>
        When you take damage while using the shield, you can use a reaction to call forth any number of the spirits named on the shield and reduce the damage by 1d10 and +1 per spirit. Alternatively, you can use the spell <em>Speak with dead</em> on one of the names, without needing the body. After using either of these effects, the name disappears and the spirit is gone.
      </p>
        <p class="indent">
          <strong>
            <em>Cursed.</em>
          </strong>
          If you die and less than 10 names are written on the shield, your spirit is trapped in it, your name appears on it, and you can't be resurrected in any way unless the shield is cleansed by a <em>Greater Restoration</em> spell.
      </p>
		</description>
	  <setters>
		  <set name="keywords">shield</set>
	    <set name="category">Homebrew Armor</set>
	    <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
	    <set name="weight" lb="6">6 lb.</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
	    <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
	    <set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
	  </setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shadowborn's Second Skin" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_SHADOWBORN_SECOND_SKIN">
	  <description>
		<p>The Shadowborn's Second Skin is a sleek and enigmatic suit of armor, tailored for those who dwell in the shadows and move unseen. Crafted from a blend of dark leather and shadow-infused silk, this armor clings to the wearer like a second skin, providing unparalleled flexibility and silence in movement. The material is imbued with shadow magic, giving it a faint, almost imperceptible shimmer that absorbs and diffuses light, making the wearer difficult to detect in dim environments.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Shadow Stalker.</em>
        </strong>
        When attuned to this armor you gain a +2 bonus on any Dexterity (Stealth) checks you make. When you are in dim light or darkness this bonus becomes +4.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Swift as Nightfall.</em>
        </strong>
        As a bonus action you can cast <em>Misty Step</em> using this armor. In a flash of darkness you teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see. You can use this feature once per day.
      </p>
	  </description>
	  <setters>
		  <set name="category">Homebrew Armor</set>
		  <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
		  <set name="weight" lb="13">13 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">body</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="enhancement">1</set>
      <set name="armor">Medium</set>
      <set name="armorClass">13 + Dex modifier</set>
      <set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LEATHER</set>
	  </setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Armor of the Warmage's Apprentice" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_WARMAGE_ARMOR">
	  <description>
		<p>The Armor of the Warmage's Apprentice is a finely crafted suit of armor designed to balance protection and arcane utility, perfect for those who are learning the ways of battle magic. Made from lightweight yet durable materials, this armor features a sleek design that allows for freedom of movement, essential for both casting spells and engaging in physical combat.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Spell Infused.</em>
        </strong>
        This armor is infused with the spell Mage Armor, granting an additional +1 AC
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Apprentice of the Arcane.</em>
        </strong>
        This armor grants a +1 bonus on all ranged spell attack rolls you make. Additionally, you deal +2 bonus damage on Evocation and Abjuration spells that deal damage.
      </p>
	  </description>
	  <setters>
		  <set name="category">Homebrew Armor</set>
		  <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
		  <set name="weight" lb="13">13 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">body</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
      <set name="enhancement">2</set>
      <set name="armor">Light</set>
      <set name="armorClass">12 + Dex modifier</set>
      <set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_STUDDED_LEATHER</set>
	  </setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Armor of the Grave" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_GRAVE_ARMOR">
	  <description>
		<p>The Armor of the Grave is a somber yet powerful suit of armor, meticulously forged with an eerie, otherworldly aesthetic. Crafted from dark, matte steel, this armor is adorned with ghostly etchings and faintly glowing runes that seem to shift and shimmer in dim light. Despite its intimidating appearance, the armor is surprisingly lightweight, allowing for ease of movement while providing robust protection.</p>
      <p>The armor grants the wearer these benefits;
        <ul>
          <li>Gain +1 to AC</li>
          <li>While you hold your breath you can chose to play dead as if effected by the <em>feign death</em> spell.</li>
          <li>You become immune to the natural effects of exhaustion.</li>
          <li>This armor protects its wearer with the <em>death ward</em> spell. Each day at dawn the armor casts <em>death ward</em> on the wearer with a duration of 24 hours.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
	  </description>
	  <setters>
		  <set name="category">Homebrew Armor</set>
		  <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
		  <set name="weight" lb="13">13 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">body</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="enhancement">1</set>
      <set name="armor">Light</set>
      <set name="armorClass">12 + Dex modifier</set>
      <set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_STUDDED_LEATHER</set>
	  </setters>
	  <rules>
		  <stat name="ac:armored:armor" value="12"/>
		  <stat name="ac:misc" value="1"/>
	  </rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Blooming Guard" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_BLOOMING_GUARD">
	  <description>
      <p>This magical shield blooms from a seed planted into the wielder's flesh, protecting and regenerating. It has 3 charges and recovers 1d4 charges every day at dawn.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Rejuvenating Petals.</em>
        </strong>
        You are continually regenerated by positive energy, you can use a reaction when suffering from necrotic damage to expend 1 charge and reduce it by 1d4 + your Constitution modifier. You roll 2d4 if you're in direct sunlight.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Psychedelic Bloom.</em>
        </strong>
        The shield's petals bloom with psychedelic patterns; you can use an action to try and hypnotize a creature that can see the shield by expending 2 charges. The target must make a DC 13 Wisdom saving throw or be incapacitated until the end of their next turn. The DC is raised by 1 if you're in direct sunlight.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Prosthetics</em>
        </strong>
        If you plant the Blooming Guard's seed in a missing arm, it is regrown as plant matter. This new arm is as functional as the missing one and rapidly wilts if your attunement to the shield is ended. You can detach and attach it as an action and it can't be removed against your will.
      </p>
	    </description>
	  <setters>
      <set name="keywords">shield</set>
	    <set name="category">Homebrew Armor</set>
	    <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
	    <set name="weight" lb="6">6 lb.</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
	    <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
	    <set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
	  </setters>
	  <rules>
	    <stat name="ac:shield" value="2" bonus="enhancement"/>
	  </rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Reel of Fortune" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_REEL_OF_FORTUNE">
	  <description>
	    <p>An ostentatious and alluring shield made in a covenant between the upper and lower planes. It seems to beckon those who gaze upon it to test their luck. While holding this shield, you have a +3 bonus to AC. While attuned to this shield you have proficiency with all gaming sets.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Jackpot.</em>
        </strong>
        When you or a creature within 60 feet of you is hit by an attack or forced to make a saving throw, you can spend any number of hit dice to cause the slots of this shield to spin. Roll a d100 and consult the following table to determine the effect;
      </p>
      <table>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <td>d100</td>
            <td>Effect</td>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>01</td>
            <td>The attack is considered a critical hit and the target automatically fails its save. Roll the hit dice. The target takes an amount of force damage equal to the roll. This damage cannot be reduced in any way. Afterwards, the target becomes vulnerable to all damage types until the start of its next turn (ignore any resistances and immunities the creature has for the duration).</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>02-05</td>
            <td>The attack is considered a critical hit and the target automatically fails its save. Roll the hit dice. The target takes an amount of force damage equal to the roll. This damage cannot be reduced in any way.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>06-20</td>
            <td>The attack is considered a critical hit and the target makes their saving throw with disadvantage. Roll the dice spent and the creature takes an amount of force damage equal to half the roll. This damage cannot be reduced in any way.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>21-45</td>
            <td>The target takes one additional dice of damage from the attack and makes their saving throw with disadvantage</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>46-55</td>
            <td>No Effect</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>56-80</td>
            <td>The target takes half damage from the attack makes their saving throw with advantage. Roll the hit dice spent and the creature regains a number of hit points equal to half the roll rounded up</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>81-95</td>
            <td>The attacking creature must reroll the d20 and use the lower roll and the target of this property makes their saving throw with advantage. Roll the hit dice spent and the creature regains a number of hit points equal to roll rounded up</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>96-99</td>
            <td>The attack automatically misses and the target automatically succeeds its save. Roll the hit dice spent and the creature regains a number of hit points equal to double the roll.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>100</td>
            <td>The target becomes immune to all damage types until the start of its next turn and automatically succeeds its save. Roll the hit dice. The target regains all its hit points and gains a number of temporary hit points equal to the roll.</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
		  <p>This shield is cursed, and attuning to it extends the curse to you. Until the curse is broken you are unwilling to part with it, keeping it within reach at all times. You cannot resist a good game of chance, taking part in any gamble or bet proposed to you no matter how potentially disastrous the outcome.</p>
     </description>
	  <setters>
      <set name="keywords">shield</set>
	    <set name="category">Homebrew Armor</set>
	    <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
	    <set name="weight" lb="6">6 lb.</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
	    <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
	    <set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
	  </setters>
	  <rules>
	    <stat name="ac:shield" value="2" bonus="enhancement"/>
	  </rules>
	</element>
	<!-- +2 robes -->
	<element name="Infernal Robes" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_ROBES">
	  <supports>ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_LIGHT</supports>
	  <description>
	    <p>These robes were weaved by the stern hand of an Infernal Webweaver under the care of Orcus the Demon Lord. These robes were specially designed for his Countess of Destruction, Nyxara Ozata to help aid her in her conquest of the material plane. The hells flow through each fiber of these robes granting the wearer Immunity to Fire damage.</p>
	  </description>
	  <setters>
	    <set name="category">Homebrew Armor</set>
	    <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
	    <set name="weight" lb="65">10 lb.</set>
	    <set name="armor">Light</set>
	    <set name="type">Armor</set>
	    <set name="slot">body</set>	    
	  </setters>
	  <rules>
	    <stat name="ac:armored:armor" value="20"/>
      <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_FIRE"/>
	  </rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Blessed Astral Plates" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_MAGIC_PLATES">
	  <supports>ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</supports>
	  <description>
		<p>This armour was forged to Vlaakith's standards under the exacting eye of a githyanki smith, resulting in the wearer receiving Resistance to Psychic damage. If the armor detects that the wearer is gith, they have Immunity to Psychic damage and whenever the wearer succeeds on a Saving throw against a spell, they regain 1d4 hit points.</p>
	  </description>
	  <setters>
		  <set name="category">Homebrew Armor</set>
		  <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
		  <set name="weight" lb="45">45 lb.</set>
		  <set name="armor">Medium</set>
		  <set name="type">Armor</set>
		  <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		  <set name="slot">body</set>
		  <set name="enhancement">3</set>
	  </setters>
	  <rules>
		  <stat name="ac:armored:armor" value="18"/>
		  <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_PSYCHIC"/>
	  </rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Astral Plates" type="Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_ARMOR_DND_HOMEBREW_PLATES">
	<description>
	    <p>This armour was forged to Vlakith's standards under the exacting eye of a githyanki smith.</p>
	    <p>This armor gives the wearer Resistance to Psychic damage and heals them if they pass a Saving throw.</p>
	</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
				<p><b>Psionic Ward:</b> If the item detects that the wearer is gith, they have Immunity to Psychic Damage.</p>
			</description>
		</sheet>
	<setters>
	    <set name="category">Homebrew Armor</set>
	    <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
	    <set name="weight" lb="55">55 lb.</set>
	    <set name="container">Heavy</set>
	    <set name="armor">Heavy</set>
	    <set name="type">Armor</set>
	    <set name="slot">body</set>  
	  </setters>
	  <rules>
	    <stat name="ac:armored:armor" value="18"/>
	    <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PSYCHIC"/>
	  </rules>
	</element>
</elements>
