<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
    <name>Subclasses</name>
    <update version="0.0.9">
      <file name="homebrew-subclasses.xml" url="https://github.com/StarsSC/Spencer-s-Homebrew-Stuff.git"/>
    </update>
  </info>
	<element name="Way of the Aftershock" type="Archetype" source="Homebrew Orithar Subclasses"
      id="ID_HOMEBREW_SUBCLASS_AFTERSHOCK">
      <description>
        <p><em>Once the name of an enigmatic Archfey who held dominion over a secluded corner of the Feywild, he spent his long existence bestowing gifts upon those who sought knowledge and deeper understanding of his realm. He believed the wonders of the Feywild were meant to be shared, not hidden away. After thousands of years, however, he fell victim to a more covetous Archfey. In death, he refused to let his power fade into nothing—his very blood became a final gift, empowering the followers who had devoted themselves to him. He believed that many acting together could leave a far greater mark on the world than any single being.</em></p>
<p class="indent"><em>Not long after his passing, the Aftershock Collective was born. Monks, scholars, and priests alike flocked to his teachings, embracing the mission he embodied in life and in death: to seek knowledge, to freely share the wisdom worthy of being spread, and to safeguard truths too dangerous for those who might misuse them.</em></p>
        <div element="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEISMIC_FIST"/>
        <div element="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VIBRATIC_ASSAULT"/>
        <div element="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIGHT_OF_THE_TREMOR"/>
        <div element="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHOCKWAVES_WRATH"/>
      </description>
      <rules>
        <grant type="Archetype Feature"
          id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEISMIC_FIST" level="3"/>
        <grant type="Archetype Feature"
          id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VIBRATIC_ASSAULT" level="7"/>
        <grant type="Archetype Feature"
          id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIGHT_OF_THE_TREMOR" level="11"/>
        <grant type="Archetype Feature"
          id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHOCKWAVES_WRATH" level="17"/>
      </rules>
    </element>
  <element name="Seismic Fist" type="Archetype Feature" source="Homebrew Orithar Subclasses"
      id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEISMIC_FIST">
      <description>
        <p>Starting when you choose this tradition at 3rd level, you gain this feature. Once per turn, you may spend 1 ki point to infuse your fists with seismic power. For the rest of the turn, when you hit a creature with your unarmed strike or monk weapon, you deal additional thunder damage equal to your wisdom modifier.</p>
      </description>
      <sheet>
        <description>May spend 1 ki point. For the rest of the turn, when you hit a creature with your unarmed strike or monk weapon, you deal additional thunder damage equal to your wisdom modifier.
        </description>
      </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Vibratic Assault" type="Archetype Feature" source="Homebrew Orithar Subclasses"
      id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VIBRATIC_ASSAULT">
      <description>
        <p>At 6th Level, you use the vibrations around you and your targets to determine their moves before they make them, allowing you to strike your enemies in a rapid onslaught before they act. You gain the following features:
        <ul>
          <li>Whenever you deal thunder damage, you may change it to force damage, and vice versa.</li>
          <li>You may add your profciency bonus to initiative rolls.</li>
          <li>On your first turn in combat, your movement speed is doubled, and you have advantage on any melee weapon attack you make.</li>
        </ul>
        </p>
      </description>
      <sheet>
        <description>May spend 1 ki point. For the rest of the turn, when you hit a creature with your unarmed strike or monk weapon, you deal additional thunder damage equal to your wisdom modifier.
        </description>
      </sheet>
    </element>
      <element name="Might of the Tremor" type="Archetype Feature" source="Homebrew Orithar Subclasses"
      id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MIGHT_OF_THE_TREMOR">
      <description>
        <p>At 11th level, you embody the raw might of the tremors of the feywild, augmenting your physical form with both increased durability and senses. You gain the following features:
          <ul>
            <li>You gain resistance to thunder damage.</li>
            <li>You gain Blindsight of 20 ft as long as you are touching solid ground. May spend 1 ki point to increase range by 10 ft, may activate multiple times.</li>
            <li>As a bonus action, may spend 1 ki point, you can anchor yourself for 1 minute. While anchored you cannot be knocked prone or moved against your will and gain temporary hit points equal to your monk level + your Wisdom modifier.</li>
          </ul>
        </p>
      </description>
      <sheet>
        <description>You gain the following features:
          <ul>
            <li>You gain resistance to thunder damage.</li>
            <li>You gain Blindsight of 20 ft on solid ground. May spend 1 ki point to increase range by 10 ft.</li>
            <li>As a bonus action, may spend 1 ki point, you can anchor yourself for 1 minute. While anchored you cannot be knocked prone or moved against your will and gain temporary hit points equal to your monk level + your Wisdom modifier.</li>
          </ul>
        </description>
      </sheet>
        <rules>
          <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_BLINDSIGHT"/>
<stat name="blindsight:range" value="20" bonus="base"/>
          <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_THUNDER"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
  <element name="Shockwaves Wrath" type="Archetype Feature" source="Homebrew Orithar Subclasses"
      id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHOCKWAVES_WRATH">
      <description>
        <p>At 17th level, you wield the power of the earth of the feywild to an extent matched only by the Fey.</p>
        <p class="indent">On your turn, you can use your action, bonus action, and 7 ki points to make a melee weapon attack against a creature you can see within 60 ft. When you do so, you leap across the battlefield to attack your target with a massive blow.</p>
        <p class="indent">This attack deals 10d10 thunder damage and deafens the target. This attack deals half damage on a miss. Additionally, all creatures, within 30 ft of the target must make a dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, they take half of the total damage, are knocked prone, and are deafened for 1 minute. On a successful save, they take a quarter of the total damage.</p>
          <p class="indent">If a creature has resistance to any damage dealt by this attack, the resistance is ignored. If a creature is immune to any damage from this attack, treat it as if it had resistance instead. You can use this feature once per long rest.</p>
      </description>
      <sheet>
        <description>On your turn, you can use your action, bonus action, and 7 ki points to make a melee weapon attack against a creature you can see within 60ft. When you do so, you leap across the battlefield to attack your target with a massive blow.
          <p class="indent">This attack deals 10d10 thunder damage and deafens the target. This attack deals half damage on a miss. Additionally, all creatures, within 30 ft of the target must make a dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, they take half of the total damage, are knocked prone, and are deafened for 1 minute. On a successful save, they take a quarter of the total damage.</p>
          <p class="indent">If a creature has resistance to any damage dealt by this attack, the resistance is ignored. If a creature is immune to any damage from this attack, treat it as if it had resistance instead. You can use this feature once per long rest.</p>
        </description>
      </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Exiled Crest" type="Archetype" source="Homebrew Orithar Subclasses"
      id="ID_HOMEBREW_SUBCLASS_EXILED_CREST">
      <supports>Martial Archetype</supports>
      <description>
        <p><em>Once the Shield of Ironspire, Now a Warrior without a Banner...</em></p>
        <p class="indent">The Exiled Crest were once the elite warriors of Ironspire, sworn protectors of the city's rulers and enforcers of its will. Betrayed, cast out, or forsaken, these warriors now walk their own path, honing their skills beyond the rigid traditions they once upheld. No longer bound by duty, they have become weapons of their own making- unpredictable, adaptable, and unrelenting.</p>
        <div element="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BROKENOATH_UNSHAKENWILL"/>
        <div element="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRESTFALLENTACTICIAN"/>
        <div element="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEFIANCEFALLEN"/>
        <div element="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MASTERLOSTCREED"/>
        <div element="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNYIELDINGPARIAH"/>
      </description>
      <sheet display="false">
        <description>The archetypal Exiled Crest focuses on several different stances to gain the advantage on the battlefield.</description>
      </sheet>
      <rules>
        <grant type="Archetype Feature"
          id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BROKENOATH_UNSHAKENWILL" level="3"/>
        <grant type="Archetype Feature"
          id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRESTFALLENTACTICIAN" level="7"/>
        <grant type="Archetype Feature"
          id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEFIANCEFALLEN" level="10"/>
        <grant type="Archetype Feature"
          id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MASTERLOSTCREED" level="15"/>
        <grant type="Archetype Feature"
          id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNYIELDINGPARIAH" level="18"/>
      </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Broken Oath, Unshaken Will" type="Archetype Feature" source="Homebrew Orithar Subclasses"
      id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BROKENOATH_UNSHAKENWILL">
      <description>
        <p>The fall from grace has only hardened your resolve. You have learned to fight without the support of a legion, adapting to any battlefield. At 3rd level, choose one of the following battlestances at the start of your turn (no action required):</p>
        <p class="indent"><em><strong>Sentinel's Aegis:</strong></em> When a creature within 5 feet of you attacks an ally, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack. You also gain a +1 bonus to AC.</p>
        <p class="indent"><em><strong>Vengeful Strike:</strong></em> The first time you take damage each round, you gain advantage on your next weapon attack and deal extra damage equal to your proficiency bonus.</p>
        <p class="indent"><em><strong>Ghost Step:</strong></em> Your speed increases by 10 feet, and you can take the Disengage or Dash action as a bonus action. Opportunity attacks against you have disadvantage.</p>
      <p>You can switch between these stances at the start of your turn.</p>
      </description>
      <sheet>
        <description>Choose one of the following battlestances at the start of your turn (no action required): <em>Sentinel's Aegis:</em>When a creature within 5 feet of you attacks an ally, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack. You also gain a +1 bonus to AC. <em>Vengeful Strike:</em> The first time you take damage each round, you gain advantage on your next weapon attack and deal extra damage equal to your proficiency bonus. <em>Ghost Step:</em> Your speed increases by 10 feet, and you can take the Disengage or Dash action as a bonus action. Opportunity attacks against you have disadvantage. You can switch between these stances at the start of your turn.
        </description>
      </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Crestfallen Tactician" type="Archetype Feature" source="Homebrew Orithar Subclasses"
      id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CRESTFALLENTACTICIAN">
      <description>
        <p>Your experience as a former Crestwatch grants you an unrivaled sense of battlefield control, at 7th level, when you roll initiative, you can immediately switch to a different stance without using an action. After hitting a creature with a melee attack, you can move 5 feet without provoking opportunity attacks.</p>
      </description>
      <sheet>
        <description>When you roll initiative, you can switch to a different stance before combat begins. After hitting a creature with a melee attack, you can move 5 feet without provoking opportunity attacks.
        </description>
      </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Defiance of the Fallen" type="Archetype Feature" source="Homebrew Orithar Subclasses"
      id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEFIANCEFALLEN">
      <description>
        <p>You refuse to kneel, no matter how dire the situation. At 10th level, when you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can use your reaction to make a Constitution saving throw (DC 10 + half the damage taken). On a success, you drop to 1 hit point instead. You can use this feature once per long rest. Additionally, you gain proficiency in Strength saving throws if you don't already have it.</p>
      </description>
      <sheet>
        <description>Once per long rest, when you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can use your reaction to make a Constitution saving throw (DC 10 + half the damage taken). On a success, you drop to 1 hit point instead.
        </description>
      </sheet>
      <rules>
        <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH"
          requirements="!ID_WOTC_PHB_MULTICLASS_FIGHTER"/>
      </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Master of the Lost Creed" type="Archetype Feature" source="Homebrew Orithar Subclasses"
      id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MASTERLOSTCREED">
      <description>
        <p>Survival has made you an expert in shifting your tactics. At 15th level, when you take damage from an attack or fail a saving throw, you can use your reaction to immediately change your battle stance. Additionally, when you use your Second Wind feature, you can switch to a different stance without using an action.</p>
      </description>
      <sheet>
        <description>When you take damage from an attack or fail a saving throw, you can use your reaction to immediately change your battle stance. Additionally, when you use your Second Wind feature, you can switch to a different stance without using an action.</description>
      </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Unyielding Pariah" type="Archetype Feature" source="Homebrew Orithar Subclasses"
      id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UNYIELDINGPARIAH">
      <description>
        <p>You have surpassed your former brethren, becoming a warrior feared across the land. At 18th level, choose two stances instead of one, benefiting from both simultaneously. Additionally, once per turn when you hit a creature with a melee attack, you can force them to make a Strength saving throw (DC 8 + proficiency bonus + Strength or Dexterity modifier). On a failure, they are either knocked prone or pushed 10 feet away (your choice).</p>
      </description>
      <sheet>
        <description>Choose two stances instead of one, benefiting from both. Additionally, once per turn when you hit a creature with a melee attack, you can force them to make a Strength saving throw (DC 8 + proficiency bonus + Strength or Dexterity modifier). On a failure, they are either knocked prone or pushed 10 feet away (your choice).</description>
      </sheet>
    </element>
  <element name="Path of the Ravaged Titan" type="Archetype" source="Homebrew Orithar Subclasses"
    id="ID_HOMEBREW_SUBCLASSES_PATH_OF_THE_RAVAGED_TITAN">
    <supports>Primal Path</supports>
    <description>
      <p><em>Scars of Orithar, Strength of the Forsaken</em></p>
      <p class="indent">The wilds of Orithar are dangerous, full of war-torn ruins, towering peaks, and restless gods. Those who walk the Path of the Ravager draw upon the ancient echoes of fallen titans, primeval spirits, and the raw fury of the land itself. These barbarians are not merely warriors- they are living embodiments of destruction and survival, wielding the chaotic power of Orithar's forsaken past.</p>
      <div element="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TITANSFURY"/>
      <div element="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORSAKENENDURANCE"/>
      <div element="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TITANSGRASP"/>
      <div element="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATHOFTITANBORN"/>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false">
      <description>The Path of the Ravaged Titan is the living remnant of Orithar's ancient power</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature"
        id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TITANSFURY" level="3"/>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature"
        id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORSAKENENDURANCE" level="6"/>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature"
        id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TITANSGRASP" level="10"/>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature"
        id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATHOFTITANBORN" level="14"/>
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Titan's Fury" type="Archetype Feature" source="Homebrew Orithar Subclasses"
    id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TITANSFURY">
    <description>
      <p>When you rage, you channel the power of Orithar's lost titans. Your body surges with supernatural strength, and your attacks carry the force of a forgotten age. At 3rd level, while raging, you gain the following benefits:</p>
      <p class="indent">Once per turn, your melee weapon attack deals an additional 1d6 force damage.</p>
      <p class="indent">When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can push it 5 feet away from you.</p>
      <p class="indent">Your Strength checks and saving throws cannot be made at disadvantage.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>While raging, you gain the following benefits: Once per turn, your melee weapon attack deals an additional 1d6 force damage. When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you may push it 5 feet away from you. Your Strength checks and saving throws cannot be made at disadvantage.
      </description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Endurance of the Forsaken" type="Archetype Feature" source="Homebrew Orithar Subclasses"
    id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FORSAKENENDURANCE">
    <description>
      <p>Your body has been shaped by the relentless hardships of Orithar, making you nearly unbreakable. At 6th level, you gain the following benefits:</p>
      <p class="indent">You have resistance to force damage.</p>
      <p class="indent">If you are under half your maximum hit points at the start of your turn, you gain temporary hit points equal to your Barbarian level.</p>
      <p class="indent">When you succeed on a Strength or Constitution saving throw against a spell or magical effect, you can use your reaction to send a shockwave in a 10-foot radius, forcing creatures of your choice to make a Strength saving throw (DC 8 + proficiency bonus + Strength modifier) or be knocked prone.</p>
    </description>
<sheet>
        <description>If you are under half your maximum hit points at the start of your turn, you gain temporary hit points equal to your Barbarian level. Additionally, when you succeed on a Strength or Constitution saving throw against a spell or magical effect, you can use your reaction to send a shockwave in a 10-foot radius, forcing creatures of your choice to make a Strength saving throw (DC 8 + proficiency bonus + Strength modifier) or be knocked prone.
        </description>
</sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FORCE"/>
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Titan's Grasp" type="Archetype Feature" source="Homebrew Orithar Subclasses"
    id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TITANSGRASP">
    <description>
      <p>You have inherited the might of Orithar's fallen colossi, allowing you to overpower any foe. At 10th level:</p>
      <p class="indent">Your carrying capacity doubles, and you count as one size larger for grappling and lifting purposes.</p>
      <p class="indent">When you hit a creature at least one size larger than you, you can force it to make a Strength saving throw (DC 8 + proficiency bonus + Strength modifier) or be staggered, giving it disadvantage on attack rolls and bility checks until the end of its next turn.</p>
      <p class="indent">When you grapple a creature, you can crush them with sheer might, dealing bludgeoning damage equal to your Strength modifier at the start of each of their turns.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When you hit a creature at least one size larger than you, you can force it to make a Strength saving throw (DC 8 + proficiency bonus + Strength modifier) or be staggered, giving it disadvantage on attack rolls and bility checks until the end of its next turn. Additionally, when you grapple a creature, you can crush them with sheer might, dealing bludgeoning damage equal to your Strength modifier at the start of each of their turns.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_WEIGHT_CAPACITY_DOUBLED"/>
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Wrath of the Titanborn" type="Archetype Feature" source="Homebrew Orithar Subclasses"
    id="ID_HOMEBREW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WRATHOFTITANBORN">
    <description>
      <p>At 14th level, you unleash the full, devastating power of Orithar's lost titans, shaking the battlefield with every strike.</p>
      <p class="indent">While raging, you can use a bonus action to slam the ground, creating a 20-foot shockwave centered on you. Each creature of your choice in the area must make a Strength saving throw (DC 8 + proficiency bonus + Strength modifier) or be knocked prone and take 4d6 force damage.</p>
      <p class="indent">Once per turn, when you take damage from an enemy within 10 feet, you can unleash a retaliatory force wave, dealing force damage equal to your Barbarian level to the attacker.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>While raging, you can use a bonus action to slam the ground, creating a 20-foot shockwave centered on you. Each creature of your choice in the area must make a Strength saving throw (DC 8 + proficiency bonus + Strength modifier) or be knocked prone and take 4d6 force damage. Once per turn, when you take damage from an enemy within 10 feet, you can unleash a retaliatory force wave, dealing force damage equal to your Barbarian level to the attacker.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  </elements>
