<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
    <name>Weapons</name>
    <update version="0.0.7">
      <file name="homebrew-weapons.xml" url="https://github.com/StarsSC/Spencer-s-Homebrew-Stuff.git"/>
    </update>
  </info>
	<element name="Simple Dagger" type="Weapon" source="Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_SIMPLE_DAGGER">
	<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_FINESSE, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_LIGHT, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_THROWN, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_DAGGER</supports>
    <description>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">2</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">onehand</set>
      <set name="range">5 ft, (20/60)</set>
      <set name="damage">1d4 piercing+1d6 necrotic</set>
      <set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_DAGGER</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="Soulshard" type="Magic Item" source="Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_SOULSHARD">
    <description>
	    <p>This magical obsidian dagger has three white crystals embedded in its hilt and a blade that never needs sharpening. It seems to exude an aura of malice.
        <ul>
          <li>When you hit with a melee attack using Soulshard you deal an additional 1d6 necrotic damage and you regain hit points equal to half the amount of necrotic damage dealt.</li>
          <li>If you reduce the target to 0 hit points, the dagger absorbs the soul of the target, causing instant death. Throughout the duration of the next short or long rest you take, one of the white crystals turns blood red and the dagger becomes a +1 weapon and deals an additional 1d6 necrotic damage. Each time you reduce a target to 0 hit points, another crystal turns red over the duration of the next short or long rest, the dagger becomes a +2 and +3 weapon for each target killed (max of 3), and each increase deals another 1d6 necrotic damage.</li>
          <li>However, for every 1d4 days that this dagger is not used to reduce a creature to 0 hit points, one of the crystals turns back to white and the dagger reverts to its less powerful form.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">2</set>
      <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Weapon</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="Weapon">Simple Dagger</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="The Offering" type="Magic Item" source="Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_OFFERING">
    <description>
	    <p>This dagger has a sharp metal blade, similar to normal daggers of its kind, but the hilt is made of leather in the shape of a human hand. Wielding this blade would make it seem as though it were a handshake. Once initiative has been rolled but before combat starts, you may choose one of these effects that will last until the end of the initiative.
    	<ul>
        <li>The blade is engulfed in a hellish flame, gain 1d8 fire damage on all damage rolls.</li>
        <li>The blade extends and is either transformed into a scimitar or a shortsword, changing the damage roll to be 1d6 Slashing.</li>
        <li>Roars of thunder echo off the blade, gain 1d8 thunder damage on all damage rolls.</li>
        <li>The River Styx coat this weapon in a unfathomable frost, deal 1d8 cold damage on all damage rolls.</li>
        <li>Light cannot determine where this weapon is at all times, whenever this weapon is thrown, it is immediately returned to the wielder.</li>
        <li>At the cost of part of your own life (1d6 hit points of your maximum is reduced) to cast the Blight spell. May increase spell level up to 9th but must increase d6 per spell level increase.</li>
        <li>Whatever obstacle troubles you, it shall know your wrath, give yourself over to me, and triumph you shall find.</li>
      </ul>
     </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">2</set>
      <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Weapon</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="Weapon">Dagger</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="Githyanki Greatsword" type="Weapon" source="Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_GITHYANKI_GREATSWORD">
    <description>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="5.4">5.4 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">twohand</set>
      <set name="range">5 ft</set>
      <set name="damage" type="slashing">2d6</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Silver Sword of the Astral Plane" type="Magic Item" source="Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_ASTRAL_SWORD">
    <supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS, ID_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE</supports>
    <description>
      <p>The holder of this item gains:
        <ul>
          <li>When wielded by a githyanki this weapon deals an additional 1d6 Psychic damage, gives the wielder an Advantage on Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma saving throws, resistance to Psychic damage, and cannot be Charmed.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="5.4">5.4 lb.</set>
      <set name="enhancement">3</set>
      <set name="type">Weapon</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="weapon">Githyanki Greatsword</set>
    </setters>
      <rules>
        <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PSYCHIC"/>
      </rules>
  </element>
  
</elements>
