<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
    <name>Weapons</name>
    <update version="0.0.5">
      <file name="homebrew-consumables.xml" url="https://github.com/StarsSC/Spencer-s-Homebrew-Stuff.git"/>
    </update>
  </info>
  <element name="Corrupt Jago" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_CORRUPT_JAGO">
  <description>
    <p>A crystaline substance forged by raw magic from the weave, unstable but useful. Corrupt Jago is of a red variety that has no helpful properties as far as mystics and scientists believe. This form of Jago tends to poison the skin of those that touch it and with enough long term exposure, can drive people mad. There have been cases with enough long term exposure or even going so far as abosrbing enough Corrupt Jago a being can transform into a mindless monster that losing all sense of themselves, becoming a bane to be reckoned with no matter who it is, friend or foe.</p>
      <p class="indent">Coming into contact with Corrupt Jago causes excrutiating pain, dealing 2d8 poison damage on the first turn you come into contact with it, increasing the damage by 1d8 for every round in contact. After 10 rounds of constant contact, your mind becomes addled and causes <strong>Confusion</strong>.</p>
  </description>
  <setters>
    <set name="category">Homebrew Consumables</set>
    <set name="weight" lb="0.1">0.1 lb.</set>
    <set name="type">Crystal</set>
    <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    <set name="stackable">true</set>
  </setters>
</element>
  <element name="Refined Jago" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_REFINED_JAGO">
  <description>
    <p>A crystaline substance forged by raw magic from the weave, unstable but useful. Typically found in its raw form, in some cases when produced it will come out to be a pure and refined version of itself or with enough magical potention, can yeidl the same results. When purified it becomes a much more potent and powerful version of itself that has less unpredicable outcomes.</p>
    <p class="indent">May spend a bonus action to absorb this piece of refined jago, the next time you cast a spell, this will cause the output to be 1 spell level higher than which it was cast, i.e. if you cast a 3rd level spell, a 3rd level spell slot will be used but it will be cast at 4th level.</p>
  </description>
  <setters>
    <set name="category">Homebrew Consumables</set>
    <set name="weight" lb="0.1">0.1 lb.</set>
    <set name="type">Crystal</set>
    <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    <set name="stackable">true</set>
  </setters>
</element>
	<element name="Jago" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_JAGO">
  <description>
    <p>A crystaline substance forged by raw magic from the weave, unstable but useful. Those who wield magic use this to help attune or amplify their abilities in the hopes of more power or understanding what they have better.</p>
    <p class="indent">May spend a bonus action to absorb this piece of Jago, the next time you cast a spell but before you roll the dice for it, roll a d100 on the Wild Magic table.</p>
  </description>
  <setters>
    <set name="category">Homebrew Consumables</set>
    <set name="weight" lb="0.1">0.1 lb.</set>
    <set name="type">Crystal</set>
    <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    <set name="stackable">true</set>
  </setters>
</element>
	<element name="Rothe's Riddle" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_ROTHES_RIDDLE">
  <description>
    <p>Created by a solitary alchemist who is said to have researched the mysterious Deep Rothes, this poinson is just as cunning as the animals themselves. To create it, you'll need some uncommon ingredients, like a drop of blood from Deep Rothe, plus the know-how to combine strong illusions with lethal effects. According to legend, the alchemist aimed to test the bravery and brains of anyone who ventured to take a taste, awarding the survivors with fresh insights and understanding into the mysteries of the Underdark.</p>
    <p class="indent">Upon ingesting or being injected with this green liquid, the drinker perceives three hostile Deep Rothes in a random unoccupied space within 25 feet, visible only to them. These illusions, incredibly lifelike, attack the drinker, dealing psychic damage with their attacks instead of their regular damage type.</p>
    <p class="indent">If the drinker damages any of the illusions, the illusions vanish. The drinker needs to make a DC 18 Wisdom saving throw, taking 6d12 psychic damage on a failure and half as much on a success. The effect then ends.</p>
    <p class="indent">If the drinker avoids harming the illusions for 30 seconds (5 turns) straight and remains conscious, the illusions dissapear and the drinker learns the Dancing Lights cantrip (even if not a spellcaster), gains proficiency in the History skill if they haven't had it already, and a permanent +1 bonus to their Intelligence score. The effect then ends.</p>
  </description>
  <setters>
    <set name="category">Homebrew Consumables</set>
    <set name="weight" lb="0.5">½ lb.</set>
    <set name="type">Poison</set>
    <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    <set name="stackable">true</set>
  </setters>
</element>
<element name="Culmados" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_CULMADOS">
  <description>
    <p>The taste of this potion is quite bitter and some may argue that the pickled catchy culm foaling in there seems a bit repulsive. Its effect, however, is said to be moving - in the most literal sense.</p>
    <p class="indent">When you drink this potion, the peculiar magic of the catchy culm flows through your body. Whenever you deal damage to a creature within 10 feet of you or you take damage from a creature within the same range, you can initiate a Charisma contest against that creature. If you win the contest, you teleport the creature to an unoccupied space of your choice within 5 feet of it. Otherwise, the creature teleports you to an unoccupied space of its choice within 5 feet of you. The potion's effect lasts for 1 minute.</p>
  </description>
  <setters>
    <set name="category">Homebrew Consumables</set>
    <set name="weight" lb="0.5">½ lb.</set>
    <set name="type">Potion</set>
    <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    <set name="stackable">true</set>
  </setters>
</element>
</elements>
