<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
    <name>Weapons</name>
    <update version="0.0.25">
      <file name="homebrew-weapons.xml" url="https://github.com/StarsSC/Spencer-s-Homebrew-Stuff.git"/>
    </update>
  </info>
  <element name="Carrion Longsword" type="Weapon" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_CARRION_LONGSWORD">
    <supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_VERSATILE, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_LONGSWORD</supports>
    <description>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">twohand</set>
      <set name="range">5 ft</set>
      <set name="damage">1d8 piercing</set>
      <set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGSWORD</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Carrion Eater" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_CARRION_EATER">
    <description>
     <p>Modeled after birds of prey, this sword was made to pierce through armor, rewarding vicious wielders. It deals piercing damage instead of slashing damage and has 3 charges, recovering 1d3 of them every day at dusk.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Talon.</em>
        </strong>
        Enchanted with a taste for death, this sword seeks enemies. You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magical weapon.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Beak.</em>
        </strong>
        When you make an attack with Carrion Eater against a creature wearing armor, you can choose to deal no damage on a hit to pierce through said armor. On a hit, roll 1d8 and reduce their AC by 1 on rolls of 1 to 5 and by 2 on rolls of 6 to 8. If this would reduce their AC without counting any ability modifier bonuses below 10, it stops at 10.
        <p class="indent">If you roll a critical hit on a creature with armor, you both deal damage and reduce their AC as written above.</p>
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Appetite.</em>
        </strong>
        Carrion Eater is sustained by death and shares its meals with you. Whenever you reduce a hostile creature to 0 hit points with an attack made with it, you can expend a number of charges to recover 1d6 hit points per charge expended.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Weapon</set>
      <set name="Weapon">Carrion Longsword</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Murder of Crows" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_MURDER_OF_CROWS">
    <description>
     <p>Gifted by the Murder, this dagger's pommel is decorated by a different trinket whenever it's unsheathed - shiny rocks, pieces of metal or colored glass shards are the most common finds. It has 3 charges that are regained every day at dusk.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Birds of a Feather.</em>
        </strong>
        When you make an attack with Murder of Crows, you can summon a spectral copy of it on your other hand. This copy disappears at the start of your next turn (or before it, if you wish to).
        <p class="indent">Additionally, you can expend 1 charge when you make a ranged attack with the original to summon it back to your hand.</p>
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Sharp Beak and Claws.</em>
        </strong>
        When you make an attack with Murder of Crows, you can spend a number of charges so the Murder aids you. You deal an extra 1d6 slashing damage per charge on a hit and you score a critical hit on a number lower than 20 per charge expended - from 17 to 20 with 3 charges, for example.
        <p class="indent">However, your critical failure chance is raised in the same way - from 1 to 4 with 3 charges, for example - and you suffer 1d6 + your Dexterity modifier slashing damage on such a failure.</p>
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="type">Weapon</set>
      <set name="Weapon">Simple Dagger</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
   <element name="Trout" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_TROUT">
    <description>
     <p>The <em>Trout</em> is a large fish, weighing rougly 3 pounds, that is enchanted with a prpensity to tell everybody and their mums that you just whacked somebody about the face with a fish. A soul-crushing moment indeed for your victims</p>
      <p>The Trout acts as a club with a +1 bonus to all attack and damage rolls.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Swings of Haste.</em>
	</strong>
            You may attack with the <em>Trout</em> up to two times in a single action if you do not already possess the ability to do so.
          </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Psychic Humiliation.</em>
	</strong>
            Each time you successfully land an attack with the <em>Trout</em>, it telepathically messages all creatures within 1 mile of you that the creature being hit has been whacked by the <em>Trout</em>.
          </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
      <set name="enhancement">1</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Weapon</set>
      <set name="Weapon">Club</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Blessing in Disguise" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_BLESSING_IN_DISGUISE">
    <description>
     <p>A Quarterstaff that looks like a dirty, run-down, beat-up stick that looks like it would crumble if you sneezed on it. Um... don't sneeze on it. Anyway, the weapon itself has 5 charges to it.</p>
       <p class="indent">
         <strong>
           <em>Blessed Weapon.</em>
         </strong>
         Despite its looks, this weapon is something that you'd want in your pack/scabbard/(eh, you get it). When you make an attack with it, you can spend a charge on it to do one of the following;
         <ul>
           <li>Cast a spell level 3 or lower</li>
           <li>Give yourself or an ally +1 on their next attack roll</li>
           <li>Give your target an extra 2d8 radiant damage</li>
         </ul>
       </p>
     <p>This weapon regains 1 charge for every hour it is in direct sunlight</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
      <set name="enhancement">1</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Weapon</set>
      <set name="Weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
        <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE"/>
      </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Sword of Armageddon" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_SWORD_OF_ARMAGEDDON">
    <description>
      <p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls with this magic weapon. While the sword is on your person, you also have resistance to fire damage.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Power of Fire.</em>
	</strong>
            You can use a bonus action to speak this magic sword's command word, causing flames to erupt from the blade. These flames shed bright light in a 40‑foot radius and dim light for an additional 40 feet. While the sword is ablaze, it deals an extra 2d6 fire damage to any target it hits. The flames last until you use a bonus action to speak the command word again or until you drop or sheathe the sword.
          </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Armageddon.</em>
        </strong>
        This sword has 3 charges. While holding it, you can use an action to expend 1 charge and cast <em>meteor swarm</em> from it (save DC 19). This property can't be used again until the next dawn. The sword regains 1d3 expended charges yearly at the dawn of the new year.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="5.4">5.4 lb.</set>
      <set name="enhancement">1</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
      <set name="type">Weapon</set>
      <set name="Weapon">Simple Greatsword</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
        <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE"/>
      </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Smart Sword" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_SMART_SWORD">
    <description>
      <p>An intelligent blade that guides you as much as you guide it. When you make an attack with this magic weaponAn intelligent blade that guides you as much as you guide it. When you make an attack with this magic weapon;
        <ul>
          <li>You add your proficiency modifier to attack rolls with this weapon, regardless of whether you have proficiency in this type of weapon or not.</li>
          <li>You ignore AC granted by Dexterity and disadvantage imposed by the Dodge action.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
      <set name="enhancement">1</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Weapon</set>
      <set name="Weapon">Simple Shortsword 2</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="Simple Shortsword 2" type="Weapon" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_SIMPLE_SHORTSWORD_2">
    <supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_FINESSE, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_LIGHT, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SHORTSWORD</supports>
    <description>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">onehand</set>
      <set name="range">5 ft</set>
      <set name="damage">1d6 piercing</set>
      <set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Zephyr Shard" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_ZEPHYR_SHARD">
    <description>
      <p>The winds of the Heavenly Dragon infuse the missiles of this bow, precise and irresistible. The DC of any of the properties of this weapon is equal to 8 + your Wisdom modifier + your proficiency bonus.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Holy Gusts</em>
        </strong>
        When you attune to this weapon, gain the following benefits;
        <ul>
        <li>While holding this bow, your walking speed increases by 10 feet and your jump distance is doubled.</li>
        <li>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls to attacks made with this magic weapon. This weapon has a number of charges equal to two times your Wisdom modifier and regains all charges on a long rest.</li>
          <li>You can use your action to spend 2 charges and call upon the Heavenly Dragon's winds to guide your arrows. You can fire a number of pieces of ammunition equal to your Wisdom modifier. Make a separate attack roll for each piece of ammunition spent, which targets a creature of your choice you can see within the normal range of this weapon.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
      <set name="enhancement">1</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Weapon</set>
      <set name="Weapon">Simple Longbow</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="Simple Longbow" type="Weapon" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_SIMPLE_LONGBOW">
    <supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_PIERCING, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_AMMUNITION, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_HEAVY, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_TWOHANDED, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_BOWS</supports>
    <description>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">twohand</set>
      <set name="range">150/600 ft</set>
      <set name="damage">1d8 piercing</set>
      <set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGBOW</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Simple Shortsword" type="Weapon" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_SIMPLE_SHORTSWORD">
    <supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_FINESSE, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_LIGHT, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SHORTSWORD</supports>
    <description>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">onehand</set>
      <set name="range">5 ft</set>
      <set name="damage">1d6 piercing+1d6 lightning</set>
      <set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="Crashing Fang" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_CRASHING_FANG">
    <description>
	    <p>A sacred blade charged with divine lightning that carries the authority of the Heavenly Dragon within itself; mighty and unstoppable.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Dragons Wrath.</em>
        </strong>
       When you attune to this weapon, gain the following benefits;
	      <ul>
		      <li>When you make a melee attack with this weapon you can use your choice of Strength or Charisma for the attack roll and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.</li>
		      <li>You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made using the weapon. On a hit, this weapon deals an additional 1d6 lightning damage.</li>
		      <li>As a bonus action while holding this weapon, you can channel the energy of the Heavenly Dragon into your enemies. For 1 minute, this weapon deals an additional 1d6 lightning damage on a hit equal to the number of times the target has been hit with this weapon this turn (ex. if a creature is hit twice in a turn with this weapon, it takes an additional 1d6 lightning damage on the first hit, and 2d6 on the second). You can use this property a number of times up to your Charisma modifier before finishing a long rest.</li>
          <li>While holding this weapon, you can cast the Haste spell targeting yourself. Once you use this property it can't be used again until you finish a short or long rest.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
      <set name="enhancement">2</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Weapon</set>
      <set name="Weapon">Simple Shortsword</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Burnt End" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_BURNT_END">
    <description>
	    <p>A dark dagger whose blade fades into sofly billowing smoke and embers. You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls you make with this magic weapon. This weapon has 3 charges and regains all charges after a long rest.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Smoking Shank.</em>
        </strong>
        While holding this weapon you can spend a charge to cast the Misty Step spell, vanishing into a puff of black smoke. If you teleport within 5 feet of another creature you can make an attack against it with this weapon as part of the spell.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Where There's Fire.</em>
        </strong>
        If you take 10 or more fire damage from a single source you can use your reaction to channel the fire into this blade and have this weapon regain a charge.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
      <set name="enhancement">2</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Weapon</set>
      <set name="Weapon">Dagger</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="The Skeleton Key" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_SKELETON_KEY">
    <description>
	    <p>An odd-looking blade that seems to hum with a power not of this world. You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls you make with this magic weapon. While attuned to this item magical effects and abilities cannot alter your physical form (ex. Enlarge/Reduce, Polymorph, etc) or ability scores in any way (ex. Belt of Giant Strength, Feeblemind, etc.) other than the Overwrite property.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Reformat.</em>
        </strong>
        As a bonus action you can reconfigure the teeth of this weapon to take on the form of any sword.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Overwrite.</em>
        </strong>
        As an action you can touch another creature with this weapon to increase or decrease an ability score of the creature by your Intelligence modifier for 1 minute or until you are knocked unconscious. An unwilling creature must succeed on a DC (8 + your Intelligence bonus + your proficiency bonus) saving throw of the ability score you are attempting to affect to resist this property. This property cannot reduce a creature's ability score below 1 or increase it beyond 30. If this property increases a creature's ability score above 25, the target gains a point of exhaustion after the effect ends. Once you use this property it can't be used again until you finish a long rest.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Malware.</em>
        </strong>
        When a creature you can see within 60 feet of you makes an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw you can have the creature roll an additional d20. You can choose to use this property after the die is rolled, but before the outcome is determined. You can choose which of the d20 is used for the attack roll, ability check, or saving throw. Once you use this property it can't be used again until you finish a long rest or you score a critical hit with this weapon.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <em>Curse: Firewall.</em>
        When you have used the Malware property of this weapon, it gains a Firewall charge. When you make an attack roll, an bility check, or a saving throw, the DM can spend a Firewall charge to have you roll an additional d20, and then choose which of the d20 you use for your roll.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
      <set name="enhancement">3</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
      <set name="type">Weapon</set>
      <set name="Weapon">Longsword</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Blackheart Butcher" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_BLACKHEART_BUTCHER">
    <description>
      <p>You gain a +1 bonus to spell attack rolls you make while holding this weapon and only spellcasters may attune. A sickly butcher's blade of cold black iron. It seethes with eldritch magicks emitting from harshly carved hex runes. While holding this weapon you can use it as an arcane focus. This weapon has 3 charges. Once per day in place of an attack you can carve at your flesh to have this item regain a charge, taking 1d10 slashing damage in the process. Alternatively, as a 1-hour ritual you can infuse the blade with sinister energies to have it regain a charge. This ritual requires at least a pound of natural animal or plant matter, regaining a charge for each pound of material which is consumed by the ritual.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Malignant Jinx.</em>
        </strong>
        While attuned to this weapon you can spend a charge to cast the Hex spell without expending a spell slot. You have advantage on concentration checks to maintain concentration on a Hex spell while attuned to this weapon.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Wretched Puppet.</em>
        </strong>
        As a bonus action you can spend a charge to make a creature within 30 feet of you the victim of your hideous magicks. The creature must make a DC 14 Charisma saving throw. If the creature is cursed by a Hex spell cast by you, the DC is raised to 16. On a failed save you choose one of the following effects to take place.
        <ul>
          <li>The creature must use its reaction to move up to 30 feet in a direction of your choice</li>
          <li>The creature must make an attack against a creature of your choice within range of them</li>
          <li>The creature falls prone. While the creature is still hexed, it must use all of its movement to stand up from prone</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Curse.</em>
        </strong>
        While attuned to this weapon you can sense the presence and direction of cursed items within 60 feet of you. When you sense a cursed item you must succeed on a DC 16 Wisdom saving throw or become compelled to seek out and attune to the item you sense. This effect ends after 1 minute or if you take damage while compelled. You gain an additional +1 bonus to spell attack rolls you make while holding this weapon for each other cursed item you are attuned to.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
      <set name="enhancement">1</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
      <set name="type">Weapon</set>
      <set name="Weapon">Scimitar</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Unseemly Sabre" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_UNSEEMLY_SABRE">
    <description>
      <p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. The cold iron of this blade emanates an eerie hostility. While a Fey creature is within 10 feet of you the blade of this weapons glows with iridescent light.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Sting of Iron.</em>
        </strong>
        When you hit a Fey creature with this weapon the target takes an additional 1d6 necrotic damage. Additionally, if the Fey's appearance is altered or their body is transformed, it must make a DC 15 Constitution saving throw. On a failure the illusion or transformation ends.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
      <set name="enhancement">1</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
      <set name="type">Weapon</set>
      <set name="Weapon">Scimitar</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="Stagweald, Forest Warden" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_STAGWEALD_FOREST_WARDEN">
    <description>
	    <p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls you make with this magic weapon. The gifted horns of woodland creatures were ritually fused to create this massive blade. While attuned, you are considered proficient with it and you may add your Wisdom modifier instead of your Strength modifier to damage and attack rolls with it. This weapon has a number of charges equal to twice your proficiency bonus and regains all charges at dawn.</p>
		    <p class="indent">
          <strong>
            <em>Evolutionary Gifts.</em>
          </strong>
          While attuned to this weapon you grow a pair of large horns from your head. These horns remain when you Wild Shape and change in size to match any form. Your horns are a natural weapon that count as simple melee weapons with which you are proficient. You add either your Strength modifier to the attack and damage rolls when you attack with these horns. On a hit this weapon deals 1d8 piercing damage and you can spend a charge to deal an amount of additional radiant damage equal to your proficiency bonus.
        </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Gouging Branch.</em>
        </strong>
        When you hit a creature with this weapon or your horns you can spend a charge to have the ends of the blade or horns pierce a creatures body. The target must make a DC 16 Strength saving throw. On a failed save the target takes 2d6 piercing damage and becomes grappled by the weapon. On a successful save the target only takes half as much damage and is not grappled. If the grappled creature breaks the grapple it takes an additional 1d6 piercing damage as the horns tear at its body. You cannot attack any creatures with the weapon other than the grappled creature as long as they remain grappled this way. You can choose to end the grapple as a bonus action, causing the horns to shrink back to their original size.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Fury of the Forest</em>
        </strong>
        As an action you can spend up to 3 charges to plunge this weapon into the ground and cause a forest of horns to burst from the earth. Each other creature within a 30-foot radius of you must make a DC 16 Dexterity saving throw, taking 6d6 piercing damage per charge on a failed save. On a successful save the target only takes half as much damage.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="6">6 lb.</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
      <set name="enhancement">2</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="type">Weapon</set>
      <set name="Weapon">Greatsword</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="Simple Dagger" type="Weapon" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_SIMPLE_DAGGER">
	<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_FINESSE, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_LIGHT, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_THROWN, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_DAGGER</supports>
    <description>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">2</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">onehand</set>
      <set name="range">5 ft, (20/60)</set>
      <set name="damage">1d4 piercing+1d6 necrotic</set>
      <set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_DAGGER</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="Soulshard" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_SOULSHARD">
    <description>
	    <p>This magical obsidian dagger has three white crystals embedded in its hilt and a blade that never needs sharpening. It seems to exude an aura of malice.
        <ul>
          <li>When you hit with a melee attack using Soulshard you deal an additional 1d6 necrotic damage and you regain hit points equal to half the amount of necrotic damage dealt.</li>
          <li>If you reduce the target to 0 hit points, the dagger absorbs the soul of the target, causing instant death. Throughout the duration of the next short or long rest you take, one of the white crystals turns blood red and the dagger becomes a +1 weapon and deals an additional 1d6 necrotic damage. Each time you reduce a target to 0 hit points, another crystal turns red over the duration of the next short or long rest, the dagger becomes a +2 and +3 weapon for each target killed (max of 3), and each increase deals another 1d6 necrotic damage.</li>
          <li>However, for every 1d4 days that this dagger is not used to reduce a creature to 0 hit points, one of the crystals turns back to white and the dagger reverts to its less powerful form.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">2</set>
      <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Weapon</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="Weapon">Simple Dagger</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="The Offering" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_OFFERING">
    <description>
	    <p>This dagger has a sharp metal blade, similar to normal daggers of its kind, but the hilt is made of leather in the shape of a human hand. Wielding this blade would make it seem as though it were a handshake. Once initiative has been rolled but before combat starts, you may choose one of these effects that will last until the end of the initiative.
    	<ul>
        <li>The blade is engulfed in a hellish flame, gain 1d8 fire damage on all damage rolls.</li>
        <li>The blade extends and is either transformed into a scimitar or a shortsword, changing the damage roll to be 1d6 Slashing.</li>
        <li>Roars of thunder echo off the blade, gain 1d8 thunder damage on all damage rolls.</li>
        <li>The River Styx coat this weapon in a unfathomable frost, deal 1d8 cold damage on all damage rolls.</li>
        <li>Light cannot determine where this weapon is at all times, whenever this weapon is thrown, it is immediately returned to the wielder.</li>
        <li>At the cost of part of your own life (1d6 hit points of your maximum is reduced) to cast the Blight spell. May increase spell level up to 9th but must increase d6 per spell level increase.</li>
        <li>Whatever obstacle troubles you, it shall know your wrath, give yourself over to me, and triumph you shall find.</li>
      </ul>
     </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">2</set>
      <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Weapon</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="Weapon">Dagger</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="Simple Greatsword" type="Weapon" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_SIMPLE_GREATSWORD">
    <description>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="5.4">5.4 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">twohand</set>
      <set name="range">5 ft</set>
      <set name="damage" type="slashing">2d6</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Silver Sword of the Astral Plane" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_ASTRAL_SWORD">
    <supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS, ID_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE</supports>
    <description>
      <p>The holder of this item gains:
        <ul>
          <li>When wielded by a githyanki this weapon deals an additional 1d6 Psychic damage, gives the wielder an Advantage on Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma saving throws, resistance to Psychic damage, and cannot be Charmed.</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Weapons</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="5.4">5.4 lb.</set>
      <set name="enhancement">3</set>
      <set name="type">Weapon</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="weapon">Simple Greatsword</set>
    </setters>
      <rules>
        <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PSYCHIC"/>
      </rules>
  </element>
  
</elements>
