<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
    <name>Wondrous Items</name>
    <update version="0.0.6">
      <file name="homebrew-backgrounds.xml" url="https://github.com/StarsSC/Spencer-s-Homebrew-Stuff.git"/>
    </update>
  </info>
  <elements>
    <info>
      <name>Hells Survivor</name>
      <description>Hells Survivor Background</description>
    </info>
    <element name="Hells Survivor" type="Background" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_BACKGROUND_HELLS_SURVIVOR">
      <description>
        <p>One fateful day, you were dragged to one of the nine layers of the hells to fend for yourself, by means of a futile attempt to live on your own, being forced into servitude by the Infernal, or other means. By some miracle, you endured and survived in your time there and managed to escape, returning to a more pleasant realm and living to tell the tale of the harshness and despair that transpired.</p>
        <ul class="unstyled">
          <li>
            <strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong>
            Athletics, Survival
          </li>
          <li>
            <strong>Languages:</strong>
            Infernal, One of your choice
          </li>
          <li>
            <strong>Equipment:</strong>
            A token of your time in the hells (such as a trophy of a prized kill or a stone from a place you travelled to), a hellweave tent, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 15 gp
          </li>
        </ul>
      </description>
        <setters>
          <set name="short">Athletics, Survival, Infernal, Language</set>
        </setters>
	<rules>
<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT"/>
<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION"/>
	<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_INFERNAL"/>	
<select type="Language" name="Language (Acolyte)" number="1" supports="Standard||Exotic"/>
<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SHELTER_OF_THE_FAITHFUL" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
<select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true"/>
<select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
<item id="1">I idolize a particular hero of my faith, and constantly refer to that person’s deeds and example.</item>
<item id="2">I can find common ground between the fiercest enemies, empathizing with them and always working toward peace.</item>
<item id="3">I see omens in every event and action. The gods try to speak to us, we just need to listen</item>
<item id="4">Nothing can shake my optimistic attitude.</item>
<item id="5">I quote (or misquote) sacred texts and proverbs in almost every situation.</item>
<item id="6">I am tolerant (or intolerant) of other faiths and respect (or condemn) the worship of other gods.</item>
<item id="7">I’ve enjoyed fine food, drink, and high society among my temple’s elite. Rough living grates on me.</item>
<item id="8">I’ve spent so long in the temple that I have little practical experience dealing with people in the outside world.</item>
</select>
<select type="List" name="Ideal">
<item id="1">Tradition. The ancient traditions of worship and sacrifice must be preserved and upheld. (Lawful)</item>
<item id="2">Charity. I always try to help those in need, no matter what the personal cost. (Good)</item>
<item id="3">Change. We must help bring about the changes the gods are constantly working in the world. (Chaotic)</item>
<item id="4">Power. I hope to one day rise to the top of my faith’s religious hierarchy. (Lawful)</item>
<item id="5">Faith. I trust that my deity will guide my actions. I have faith that if I work hard, things will go well. (Lawful)</item>
<item id="6">Aspiration. I seek to prove myself worthy of my god’s favor by matching my actions against his or her teachings. (Any)</item>
</select>
<select type="List" name="Bond">
<item id="1">I would die to recover an ancient relic of my faith that was lost long ago.</item>
<item id="2">I will someday get revenge on the corrupt temple hierarchy who branded me a heretic.</item>
<item id="3">I owe my life to the priest who took me in when my parents died.</item>
<item id="4">Everything I do is for the common people.</item>
<item id="5">I will do anything to protect the temple where I served.</item>
<item id="6">I seek to preserve a sacred text that my enemies consider heretical and seek to destroy.</item>
</select>
<select type="List" name="Flaw">
<item id="1">I judge others harshly, and myself even more severely.</item>
<item id="2">I put too much trust in those who wield power within my temple’s hierarchy.</item>
<item id="3">My piety sometimes leads me to blindly trust those that profess faith in my god.</item>
<item id="4">I am inflexible in my thinking.</item>
<item id="5">I am suspicious of strangers and expect the worst of them.</item>
<item id="6">Once I pick a goal, I become obsessed with it to the detriment of everything else in my life.</item>
</select>
</rules>  
</element>
  </elements>
</elements>
