<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
    <name>Armor</name>
    <update version="0.0.16">
      <file name="homebrew-armor.xml" url="https://github.com/StarsSC/Spencer-s-Homebrew-Stuff.git"/>
    </update>
  </info>
	<element name="Blooming Guard" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_BLOOMING_GUARD">
	  <description>
      <p>This magical shield blooms from a seed planted into the wielder's flesh, protecting and regenerating. It has 3 charges and recovers 1d4 charges every day at dawn.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Rejuvenating Petals.</em>
        </strong>
        You are continually regenerated by positive energy, you can use a reaction when suffering from necrotic damage to expend 1 charge and reduce it by 1d4 + your Constitution modifier. You roll 2d4 if you're in direct sunlight.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Psychedelic Bloom.</em>
        </strong>
        The shield's petals bloom with psychedelic patterns; you can use an action to try and hypnotize a creature that can see the shield by expending 2 charges. The target must make a DC 13 Wisdom saving throw or be incapacitated until the end of their next turn. The DC is raised by 1 if you're in direct sunlight.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Prosthetics</em>
        </strong>
        If you plant the Blooming Guard's seed in a missing arm, it is regrown as plant matter. This new arm is as functional as the missing one and rapidly wilts if your attunement to the shield is ended. You can detach and attach it as an action and it can't be removed against your will.
      </p>
	    </description>
	  <setters>
      <set name="keywords">shield</set>
	    <set name="category">Homebrew Armor</set>
	    <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
	    <set name="weight" lb="6">6 lb.</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
	    <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
	    <set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
	  </setters>
	  <rules>
	    <stat name="ac:shield" value="2" bonus="enhancement"/>
	  </rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Reel of Fortune" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_REEL_OF_FORTUNE">
	  <description>
	    <p>An ostentatious and alluring shield made in a covenant between the upper and lower planes. It seems to beckon those who gaze upon it to test their luck. While holding this shield, you have a +3 bonus to AC. While attuned to this shield you have proficiency with all gaming sets.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Jackpot.</em>
        </strong>
        When you or a creature within 60 feet of you is hit by an attack or forced to make a saving throw, you can spend any number of hit dice to cause the slots of this shield to spin. Roll a d100 and consult the following table to determine the effect;
      </p>
      <table>
        <thead>
          <tr>
            <td>d100</td>
            <td>Effect</td>
          </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <tr>
            <td>01</td>
            <td>The attack is considered a critical hit and the target automatically fails its save. Roll the hit dice. The target takes an amount of force damage equal to the roll. This damage cannot be reduced in any way. Afterwards, the target becomes vulnerable to all damage types until the start of its next turn (ignore any resistances and immunities the creature has for the duration).</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>02-05</td>
            <td>The attack is considered a critical hit and the target automatically fails its save. Roll the hit dice. The target takes an amount of force damage equal to the roll. This damage cannot be reduced in any way.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>06-20</td>
            <td>The attack is considered a critical hit and the target makes their saving throw with disadvantage. Roll the dice spent and the creature takes an amount of force damage equal to half the roll. This damage cannot be reduced in any way.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>21-45</td>
            <td>The target takes one additional dice of damage from the attack and makes their saving throw with disadvantage</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>46-55</td>
            <td>No Effect</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>56-80</td>
            <td>The target takes half damage from the attack makes their saving throw with advantage. Roll the hit dice spent and the creature regains a number of hit points equal to half the roll rounded up</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>81-95</td>
            <td>The attacking creature must reroll the d20 and use the lower roll and the target of this property makes their saving throw with advantage. Roll the hit dice spent and the creature regains a number of hit points equal to roll rounded up</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>96-99</td>
            <td>The attack automatically misses and the target automatically succeeds its save. Roll the hit dice spent and the creature regains a number of hit points equal to double the roll.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>100</td>
            <td>The target becomes immune to all damage types until the start of its next turn and automatically succeeds its save. Roll the hit dice. The target regains all its hit points and gains a number of temporary hit points equal to the roll.</td>
          </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
		  <p>This shield is cursed, and attuning to it extends the curse to you. Until the curse is broken you are unwilling to part with it, keeping it within reach at all times. You cannot resist a good game of chance, taking part in any gamble or bet proposed to you no matter how potentially disastrous the outcome.</p>
     </description>
	  <setters>
      <set name="keywords">shield</set>
	    <set name="category">Homebrew Armor</set>
	    <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
	    <set name="weight" lb="6">6 lb.</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
	    <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
	    <set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
	  </setters>
	  <rules>
	    <stat name="ac:shield" value="2" bonus="enhancement"/>
	  </rules>
	</element>
	<!-- +2 robes -->
	<element name="Infernal Robes" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_ROBES">
	  <supports>ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_LIGHT</supports>
	  <description>
	    <p>These robes were weaved by the stern hand of an Infernal Webweaver under the care of Orcus the Demon Lord. These robes were specially designed for his Countess of Destruction, Nyxara Ozata to help aid her in her conquest of the material plane. The hells flow through each fiber of these robes granting the wearer Immunity to Fire damage.</p>
	  </description>
	  <setters>
	    <set name="category">Homebrew Armor</set>
	    <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
	    <set name="weight" lb="65">10 lb.</set>
	    <set name="armor">Light</set>
	    <set name="type">Armor</set>
	    <set name="slot">body</set>	    
	  </setters>
	  <rules>
	    <stat name="ac:armored:armor" value="20"/>
      <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_FIRE"/>
	  </rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Blessed Astral Plates" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_MAGIC_PLATES">
	  <supports>ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</supports>
	  <description>
		<p>This armour was forged to Vlaakith's standards under the exacting eye of a githyanki smith, resulting in the wearer receiving Resistance to Psychic damage. If the armor detects that the wearer is gith, they have Immunity to Psychic damage and whenever the wearer succeeds on a Saving throw against a spell, they regain 1d4 hit points.</p>
	  </description>
	  <setters>
		  <set name="category">Homebrew Armor</set>
		  <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
		  <set name="weight" lb="45">45 lb.</set>
		  <set name="armor">Medium</set>
		  <set name="type">Armor</set>
		  <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		  <set name="slot">body</set>
		  <set name="enhancement">3</set>
	  </setters>
	  <rules>
		  <stat name="ac:armored:armor" value="18"/>
		  <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_PSYCHIC"/>
	  </rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Astral Plates" type="Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_ARMOR_DND_HOMEBREW_PLATES">
	<description>
	    <p>This armour was forged to Vlakith's standards under the exacting eye of a githyanki smith.</p>
	    <p>This armor gives the wearer Resistance to Psychic damage and heals them if they pass a Saving throw.</p>
	</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
				<p><b>Psionic Ward:</b> If the item detects that the wearer is gith, they have Immunity to Psychic Damage.</p>
			</description>
		</sheet>
	<setters>
	    <set name="category">Homebrew Armor</set>
	    <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
	    <set name="weight" lb="55">55 lb.</set>
	    <set name="container">Heavy</set>
	    <set name="armor">Heavy</set>
	    <set name="type">Armor</set>
	    <set name="slot">body</set>  
	  </setters>
	  <rules>
	    <stat name="ac:armored:armor" value="18"/>
	    <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PSYCHIC"/>
	  </rules>
	</element>
</elements>
