<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
    <name>Wondrous Items</name>
    <update version="0.0.43">
      <file name="homebrew-wonders.xml" url="https://github.com/StarsSC/Spencer-s-Homebrew-Stuff.git"/>
    </update>
  </info>
	<element name="Greaves of Chain Lightning" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_GREAVES_OF_CHAIN_LIGHTNING">
    <description>
	    <p>These finely crafted leather and iron greaves crackle with arcane lightning. As a bonus action, you can activate the greaves, gaining the following benefits for 1 minute:
		    <p class="indent">
			    <strong>
				    <em>Galvanic Charge.</em>
			    </strong>
			    You gain resistance to lightning damage, and your attacks deal an additional 1d6 lightning damage on a hit.</p>
		    <p class="indent">
			    <strong>
				    <em>Bolt.</em>
			    </strong>
			    Your speed increases by 10 feet. Additionally, you can take the Dash action as a bonus action on each of your turns for the duration.</p>
		    <p>Once you activate the greaves, you can't do so again until you finish a long rest. If you score a critical hit or are subjected to a critical hit while the greaves are active, you gain one additional use of this ability. This additional use must be expended before your next long rest.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">athletics</set>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">legs</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="Shifter Arrow" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_SHIFTER_ARROW">
    <description>
	    <p>This arrow has an arrowhead engraved with 3 golden teardrops that seem to shimmer moreso in the sunlight.</p>
	    <p class="indent">
		    <strong>
			    <em>Shift.</em>
		    </strong>
		    Whenever you fire this arrow, you may choose to have this arrow come back to you or if not, summon a spectral arrow to take its place to fire.
	    </p>
	    <p class="indent">
		    <strong>
			    <em>Bloodlust.</em>
		    </strong>
		    Attacks against the same target increase in damage by 2 for each consecutive hit. There is no limit to the damage, just in what you give for it.
	    </p>
		    <p class="indent">
			    <strong>
				    <em>Cursed.</em>
			    </strong>
			    You cannot get rid of this arrow, it is eternally soulbound to the wielder.
		    </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Unique</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="Bracer of the Emerald Stag" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_BRACER_OF_EMERALD_STAG">
    <description>
	    <p>May only be attuned to a Cleric, Paladin, or Ranger.</p>
	    <p class="indent">
		    <strong>
			    <em>Thundering Hooves.</em>
		    </strong>
		    If you make a ranged weapon attack while attuned to this bracer you may use a bonus action to empower the attack with this bracer. On a successful hit the attack deals an extra 3d8 Thunder damage. You can use this feature twice per long rest.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Blessing of the Stag.</em>
        </strong>
        You can use an action to heal and inspire one creature within 30ft. of you using this bracer. Make a Nature check, the creature heals for an amount equal to that number. Additionally, they gain a d8 Inspiration die which they can use on any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check within the next 10 minutes. You can use this feature once per long rest.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">athletics</set>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">hands</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Crown of the Great Wolf" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_CROWN_OF_GREAT_WOLF">
    <description>
<p class="indent">
  <strong>
    <em>Mind of the Wolf.</em>
  </strong>
  While attuned to this crown you have darkvision up to 90ft. You are immune to being Frightened or Charmed and have advantage on saving throws against being Stunned. Additionally you may add your proficiency bonus to Survival checks you make to track other creatures.
</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
        <em>Final Battle.</em>
        </strong>
        If you drop to 0 hit points while attuned to this crown, you regain 5d12 hit points when you roll a successful death save or when you regain any number of hit points. You can benefit from this feature once per long rest
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Parts of a Whole.</em>
        </strong>
        If you are also attuned to the Hide of the Great Wolf, the AC of that armor increases by 1. If you are attuned to the Gloves of the Great Wolf, they deal 1d8 Necrotic damage instead of 1d6.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">head</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION"/>
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Gloves of the Great Wolf" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_GLOVES_OF_GREAT_WOLF">
    <description>
      <p>Requires attunement by a Druid or Monk</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Dark Claws.</em>
        </strong>
        When wearing these gauntlets, your unarmed strikes deal an extra 1d6 Necrotic damage. This bonus is also applied to attacks you make while you are Wild Shaped or Polymorphed.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Bloodthirst.</em>
        </strong>
        Whenever you reduce a creature to 0 hit points, you gain advantage on your next attack roll within the next minute.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Ravager of the Divine.</em>
        </strong>
        Whenever you receive Fire, Lightning, Radiant, or Thunder damage, you may use your reaction to reduce that damage. Make a Wisdom saving throw. The DC equals 10 or a number equal to half of the damage, whichever is higher. On a successful save you reduce the damage by 2d6+ your Wisdom modifier. You may use this feature twice per long rest.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">athletics</set>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">hands</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Satchel of Sustenance" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_SUSTENANCE_SATCHEL">
    <description>
	<p>The Satchel of Sustenance is a remarkable and essential item for any adventurer, crafted from durable, enchanted leather with intricate embroidery depicting scenes of bountiful harvests and feasts. This satchel combines the expansive capacity of a bag of holding with unique magical properties specifically attuned to preserving and providing nourishment. The interior of the Satchel of Sustenance is vast, capable of holding an impressive array of items without ever becoming cumbersome. What sets this satchel apart is its ability to preserve food indefinitely; no matter how long it is stored, food remains fresh and unspoiled, ready to be consumed at any time.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Extradimensional Stockpile</em>
        </strong>
        This bag functions as a Bag of Holding with the extra property that food and drink does not decay when it is stored inside the bag.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Commoner's Feast.</em>
        </strong>
        You can put a gold coin in the bag and speak a command word which consumes the coin. The bag fills with enough food and drink to sustain 5 humanoids for 1 day. The food consists of various breads, nuts, fruits, vegetables and raw meats. The drinks are an assortement of juices and fresh water. The satchel can store up to 10 of these feasts before it is completely filled up. You can use this feature 5 times per day.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="15">15 lb.</set>
      <set name="stash" lb="500" weightless="true">true</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="Immortal Amulet" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_IMMORTAL_AMULET">
    <description>
	<p>The amulet deepens your connection with death. You can use an action to touch a corpse or undead to experieence a short sequence of images on its final moments before death. Once you use this feature you cannot do so again until the next dawn.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">neck</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
	<element name="Moonsliver Cloak" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_MOONSLIVER_CLOAK">
    <description>
     <p>The Moonsliver Cloak is an enchanting garment woven from the finest silken threads, imbued with the ethereal essence of moonlight itself. This cloak, lightweight and flowing, shimmers with a delicate silvery hue, reminiscent of the moon's glow on a clear night. The fabric is soft to the touch, yet incredibly durable, designed to withstand the rigors of any adventure.</p>
      <p>The cloak grants the wearer these benefits;
        <ul>
          <li>The wearer may become invisible as a bonus action while outdoors in moonlight</li>
          <li>+1 to AC and all saving throws</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">cloak</set>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">shoulders</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
      <stat name="ac:misc" value="1"/>
      <stat name="strength:save:misc" value="1"/>
      <stat name="dexterity:save:misc" value="1"/>
      <stat name="constitution:save:misc" value="1"/>
      <stat name="intelligence:save:misc" value="1"/>
      <stat name="wisdom:save:misc" value="1"/>
      <stat name="charisma:save:misc" value="1"/>
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Hood of the Dragonturtle" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_DRAGONTURTLE_HOOD">
    <description>
      <p>The Hood of the Dragonturtle is a majestic and awe-inspiring piece of headgear, crafted with the scales and essence of the legendary Dragonturtle. This hood is renowned for its distinctive design, which combines the robust, textured scales of the Dragonturtle with elegant craftsmanship. The scales shimmer with hues of deep green, azure, and hints of gold, reflecting the mystical aura of its origin.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Fortitude of the Deep.</em>
        </strong>
        When you are attuned to this hood you gain a +4 to your Constitution ability score.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Dark Ocean Ancestry.</em>
        </strong>
        You gain Darkvision up to 120ft. Additionally you can breathe underwater.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Steam Breath.</em>
        </strong>
        As an action, you exhale steam in a 20ft cone. Each creature in that area has to make a Constitution saving throw (DC 18). Taking 2d8 Fire damage on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful save. The damage increases to 3d8 at 6th level, 4d8 at 11th level, and 5d8 at 16th level. You can not use this feature again until you finish a short or a long rest. Being underwater doesn't grant resistance against this damage.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">head</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION"/>
      <stat name="constitution" value="4"/>
      <stat name="ac:misc" value="1"/>
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Cloak of Solitude" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_CLOAK_OF_SOLITUDE">
    <description>
      <p>The Cloak of Solitude was crafted centuries ago by the enigmatic sorceress Elandra, known for her deep wisdom and solitary nature. Elandra, seeking refuge from a world filled with treachery and deceit, imbued the cloak with powerful enchantments to protect herself from the myriad poisons of her enemies. The forcefield, a unique feature of the cloak, was added to ensure her peace and solitude, gently pushing away any who attempted to intrude upon her sanctuary. Legends say that Elandra wove her longing for solitude into every thread, creating an artifact that not only shields its wearer from harm but also grants them the tranquility she so desperately sought. The cloak has since passed through the hands of many, each owner finding in it a profound sense of protection and peace.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Self-Isolation.</em>
        </strong>
        You have advantage on all Constitution saving throws whenever there is no other creature within 5ft. of you.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Antidote.</em>
        </strong>
        You can cast the spell Protection from Poison using this cloak. You can use this feature once per long rest.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Master of Distancing.</em>
        </strong>
        As an action you create a short burst of an arcane forcefield around you. All creatures within 5ft. of you have to make a Strength saving throw (DC10 + your Constitution modifier). On a failed save they are pushed 5ft. away from you. You can use this feature twice per long rest.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">cloak</set>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">shoulders</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
    <rules>
      <stat name="constitution:save:misc" value="1"/>
    </rules>
  </element>
	<element name="Firedrake's Grasp" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_FIREDRAKE_GRASP">
    <description>
      <p>Crafted by Orcus the Demon Lords subservients out of the scales of a dragon, made to empower their vassal knights, this gauntlet gifts those who wear it with the draconic aspect of rending claws and fiery blood.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Burning Touch.</em>
        </strong>
        The gauntlet burns with a deep heat that does not harm you. While grappling a creature, you can use a bonus action to deal 1d4 fire damage to them.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Claws of Flame.</em>
        </strong>
        While wearing the gauntlet, your unarmed attacks are improved. They deal 1d6 fire or slashing damage plus your Charisma Modifier. If you have the martial arts class feature, you can use your unarmed damage die and still choose to deal fire or flashing damage with your unarmed attacks.
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <strong>
          <em>Firedrake's Breath</em>
        </strong>
        You can use an action to produce a torrent of flames from the gauntlet in a 20-foot cone. Each creature inside it must make a DC 14 Dexterity saving throw or suffer 5d6 + your Charisma modifier fire damage. You can do so once per long rest.
      </p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="keywords">athletics</set>
      <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
      <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
      <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
      <set name="slot">hands</set>
      <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
      <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
    </setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Cosmic Coronet" type="Magic Item" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_WOTC_DND_HOMEBREW_COSMIC_CORONET">
  <description>
    <p>The thrall of cosmic power, of infinite potential; who could resist? A golden crown roiling with interstellar energy. While attuned to this item you can speak, read, and write Celestial can use it as an arcane focus. This item has 4 charges and regains 1d4 charges daily at dawn. Through time, accomplishment, and growth, this item can grow into its Awakened state, then into its Exalted state (according to your DM).
    </p>
    <p class="indent">
      <strong>
        <em>Dormant.</em>
      </strong>
      The crown grants the following benefits in its dormant state;
        <ul><li>While attuned to this item you gain a +1 bonus to spell attack rolls.</li>
	<li><em>Protostar.</em> When you roll for damage as a result of a spell that targets a single creature you can spend up to 3 charges to increase the amount of damage dice you roll by the number of charges spent.</li>
	</ul>
      </p>
	  <p class="indent">
		  <strong>
			  <em>Awakened.</em>
		  </strong>
		  When the crown reaches an awakened state, it gains the following properties;
		  <ul>
			  <li>You gain a +2 bonus to spell attack rolls.</li>
        <li>This item now can hold up to 6 charges and regains 1d6+1 charges daily at dawn.</li>
        <li><em>Black Hole.</em> When you or a creature within 40 feet of you is targeted by a spell of 6th level or lower that targets only a single creature, you can use your reaction to absorb the magic of the spell, canceling its effect. This item then gains a number of charges equal to the level of the absorbed spell. Once you use this property it can't be used again until to finish a long rest.</li>
		  </ul>
	  </p>
    <p class="indent">
      <strong>
        <em>Exalted.</em>
      </strong>
      When the crown reaches an exalted state, it gains the following properties;
      <ul>
        <li>You gain a +3 bonus to spell attack rolls</li>
        <li>This item now can hold up to 8 charges and regains 1d8+2 charges daily at dawn</li>
        <li><em>Constellation.</em> You can spend 7 charges to cast the Crown of Stars spell. Once you use this property, it cannot be used again for 1d6+1 number of days. When you make a spell attack against a creature with a mote created by the Crown of Stars spell while attuned to this item, you can use the Protostar property to increase the number of damage dice you roll for that spell attack.</li>
        <li><em>Shooting Star.</em> You can cast the Wish spell without expending a spell slot. When you cast the spell through this item, your attunement to it is broken and this item vanishes, back to the realm from whence it came.</li>
      </ul>
    </p>
  </description>
	  <setters>
		  <set name="category">Homebrew Wondrous Items</set>
		  <set name="cost" currency="gp">N/A</set>
		  <set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
		  <set name="slot">head</set>
		  <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
		  <set name="attunement">true</set>
		  <set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
	  </setters>
  </element>
</elements>
