<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
    <name>Wondrous Items</name>
    <update version="0.0.10">
      <file name="spells.xml" url="https://github.com/StarsSC/Spencer-s-Homebrew-Stuff.git"/>
    </update>
  </info>
  <element name="Sorcerous Burst" type="Spell" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SORCEROUS_BURST">
<supports>Sorcerer</supports>
<description>
<p>You cast sorcerous energy at one creature or object within range. Make a ranged attack roll against the target. On a hit, the target takes 1d8 damage of a type you choose: Acid, Cold, Fire, Lightning, Poison, Psychic, or Thunder. If you roll an 8 on a d8 for this spell, you can roll another d8, and add it to the damage. When you cast this spell, the maximum number of these d8s you can add to the spell’s damage equals your spellcasting ability modifier.</p>
</description>
<setters>
<set name="keywords">necrotic</set>
<set name="level">0</set>
<set name="school">Evocation</set>
<set name="time">1 action</set>
<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
<set name="range">60 feet</set>
<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
<set name="materialComponent"/>
<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
<set name="isRitual">false</set>
</setters>
</element>
  <element name="Cruel Word: Sever" type="Spell" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CRUEL_WORD_SEVER">
<supports>Bard, Cleric, Sorcerer, Warlock</supports>
<description>
  <p>You unleash a word steeped in disdain, attempting to unravel a creature's mystical connection to its source of power. Choose one creature within range that is capable of casting spells. The target must make a saving throw using its spellcasting ability modifier. On a successful save, the creature takes 7d6 psychic damage. On a failed save, the creature is cut off from its power source and is unable to cast spells using a spell slot of 4th level or higher for the duration.</p>
  <p class="indent">Whenever the creature attempts to cast a spell of 1st level or higher, it must make another saving throw using its spellcasting ability modifier. On a failed save, the creature takes 1d10 force damage per level of the spell attempted, and the spell fails. On a successful save, the spell is cast as normal. If the creature succeeds on this saving throw three times, this spell ends for that creature.</p>
  <p class="indent">If <em>Cruel Word: Sever</em> lasts for the full duration or if the creature fails three saving throws while attempting to cast spells during the duration, the effect becomes permanent until removed. This effect can only be dispelled by <em>remove curse</em> spell cast at a level equal to or higher than the original casting level of <em>Cruel Word: Sever</em>. A <em>remove curse</em> cast at a lower level allows the creature to cast spells of that level and lower for a number of hours equal to the level of the spell slot used.</p>
</description>
<setters>
<set name="keywords">cruel word</set>
<set name="level">7</set>
<set name="school">Enchantment</set>
<set name="time">1 action</set>
<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
<set name="range">60 feet</set>
<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
<set name="materialComponent"/>
<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
<set name="isRitual">false</set>
</setters>
</element>
	<element name="Cruel Word: Defile" type="Spell" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CRUEL_WORD_DEFILE">
<supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Warlock</supports>
<description>
  <p>A word of malice passes your lips, warping the features of a creature and sifiguring them in a grotesque way. The target must make a Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, the target takes 6d6 necrotic damage and becomes disfigured. On a successful save, the target does not become disfigured.</p>
  <p class="indent">A disfigured creature suffers the following:
    <ul>
      <li>Its Charisma score is reduced by 3 (to a minimum of 1) and it has disadvantage on Charisma Checks and Saving Throws.</li>
      <li>If the creature is targeted by the <em>Vicious Mockery</em> cantrip, it automatically fails the saving throw and takes maximum damage from the spell.</li>
      <li>Once per day, when the creature gazes upon its disfigured form in a reflective surface it is affected by the <em>Vicious Mockery</em> cantrip (4d6 psychic damage). In addition, after each long rest the creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failure, it suffers a -2 penalty to all D20 tests until its next long rest, as it is reminded of its hideous form and loses confidence in themselves.</li>
    </ul>
  </p>
  <p class="indent">A disfigured creature can repeat the saving throw after 6 hours. On a success, the spell ends. On a failure, the effect persists, and the creature may repeat the saving throw after 6 days, ending the effect on a success. If a creature fails the saving throw three times, the effect becomes permanent until removed by greater restoration, wish, or similar magic.</p>
</description>
<setters>
<set name="keywords">cruel word</set>
<set name="level">6</set>
<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
<set name="time">1 action</set>
<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
<set name="range">60 feet</set>
<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
<set name="materialComponent"/>
<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
<set name="isRitual">false</set>
</setters>
</element>
	<element name="Cruel Word: Agony" type="Spell" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CRUEL_WORD_AGONY">
<supports>Bard, Cleric, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
<description>
  <p>You utter a word of pure anguish, condemning a creature within range to experience excruciating pain. Choose one of the following effects when you cast this spell:</p>
  <p class="indent">
    <strong>
      <em>Torment the Flesh.</em>
    </strong>
    The target must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the target takes 12d6 necrotic damage, falls prone, and has its speed reduced to 0. In addition, the target suffers a cumulative -1 penalty to Strength and Dexterity ability checks and saving throws rolls for each 6 rolled on the damage dice.</p>
  <p class="indent">
    <strong>
      <em>Torment the Mind.</em>
    </strong>
    The target must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the target takes 12d6 psychic damage, falls prone, and has its speed reduced to 0. In addition, the target suffers a cumulative -1 penalty to Intelligence and Charisma ability checks, saving throws, and concentration saving throws for each 6 rolled on the damage dice.</p>
  <p>The effect of this spell last until the start of your next turn. On a successful save, the target takes half as much damage and suffers none of the spell's other effects.</p>
  <p class="indent">
    <strong>
      <em>A Taste of Suffering.</em>
    </strong>
    Whenever you roll a 6 on a damage die for this spell, you may re-roll one other damage die that is not a 6. If you ever roll a 6 on all 12 damage dice, the final damage dealt is multiplied by 6.</p>
</description>
<setters>
<set name="keywords">cruel word</set>
<set name="level">6</set>
<set name="school">Enchantment</set>
<set name="time">1 action</set>
<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
<set name="range">60 feet</set>
<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
<set name="materialComponent"/>
<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
<set name="isRitual">false</set>
</setters>
</element>
<element name="Drain Life" type="Spell" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DRAIN_LIFE">
<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Warlock</supports>
<description>
<p>You point your finger to a creature to siphon its life force. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, target takes 1d6 necrotic damage, and you regain hit points equal to half the amount of necrotic damage dealt.</p>
<p class="indent">The spell's damage increases by 1d6 at 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6).</p>
</description>
<setters>
<set name="keywords">necrotic</set>
<set name="level">0</set>
<set name="school">Necromancy</set>
<set name="time">1 action</set>
<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
<set name="range">60 feet</set>
<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
<set name="materialComponent"/>
<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
<set name="isRitual">false</set>
</setters>
</element>
	<element name="Echo Bolt" type="Spell" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ECHO_BOLT">
<supports>Wizard</supports>
<description>
 <p>You fire a bolt of force that deals 1d6 force damage, and on your next turn, it fires again at the same target automatically without the use of another action.</p>
   <p class="indent">This spell's damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6)</p>
</description>
<setters>
<set name="keywords">force, causamancy</set>
<set name="level">0</set>
<set name="school" addition="Causamancy">Evocation</set>
<set name="time">1 action</set>
<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
<set name="range">60 feet</set>
<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
<set name="materialComponent"/>
<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
<set name="isRitual">false</set>
</setters>
</element>
  	<element name="Memory Echo" type="Spell" source="Spencer's Homebrew" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MEMORY_ECHO">
<supports>Wizard</supports>
<description>
 <p>Touch a surface or creature. You learn the strongest memory or magical event that occurred there in the last 24 hours. Gain advantage on Arcana or Insight checks related to it.</p>
</description>
<setters>
<set name="keywords">causamancy</set>
<set name="level">2</set>
<set name="school" addition="Causamancy">Divination</set>
<set name="time">1 action</set>
<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
<set name="range">Touch</set>
<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
<set name="materialComponent">A sliver of polished obsidian worth 25 gp</set>
<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
<set name="isRitual">true</set>
</setters>
</element>
</elements>
